华纳
兄弟
影视
公司
时代华纳旗下公司
威秀影业
拉特帕克
娱乐
「制作」越空行者
■
华纳影视公司
出品
与威秀影业联合出版
与拉特帕克娱乐联合出版
疯狂时机公司制作
22号&印第安纳制作
马尔帕索公司制作
美国狙击手
这里真他妈热
It's a fucking hotbox.
这的泥巴尝起来就像狗屎一样
Man, the fucking dirt here tastes like dog shit.
-说的你好像吃过一样？ -闭上你的臭嘴
- Oh, well, you'd know, wouldn't you? - Shut the fuck up.
我看到有个正在打电话的可疑作战人员
I got a military-age male
他正看着车队，完毕
that's on a cell phone watching the convoy, over.
如果你认为他在汇报车队动向
If you think he's reporting troop movement,
你的一切行动获得准许  你来决定，完毕
you have a green light. Your call. Over.
他可能只是打给他老妈
Maybe he's just calling his old lady.
他走了
He stepped off.
等等  我看到一个女人带着孩子
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid,
200码远  正往车队方向走去
200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
她的手臂没有摆动  她带着一些东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿了一个手榴弹
Yeah, she's got a grenade.
她刚刚把一个俄制RKG手榴弹给了那个小孩
She's got an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你是说一个女人和一个小孩？
You say a woman and a kid?
你看见了？确定吗？
- You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?
没有  你知道交战规则  你来决定
- Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
如果你搞错了 他们会炒了你
Man, they fry you if you're wrong.
然后一脚把你踢到莱文沃思（军事监狱）
They send your ass to Leavenworth.
你打到了
You got him.
嘿  过来
Hey, get back here!
你永远都不要把你的枪丢到地上  -好的
- You don't ever leave your rifle in the dirt. - Yes, sir.
孩子 刚刚那枪很棒  你很有天赋
That was a hell of a shot, son. You got a gift.
你以后会成为一个出色的猎人
You're gonna make a fine hunter someday.
在《使徒行传》中...
Here in the book of acts,
保罗多次判断...
several times, Paul stands in judgment
自己的信仰
for what he believes.
有时候  我们都要那样
And at times, we all have to do that.
我是说 我们没有站在他的立场...
I mean, we don't see with his eyes,
所以我们不知道他所做的意义
so we don't know the glory of his plan.
展现在我们面前的生活 就像镜子里令人不解的镜像
Our lives unfold before us like puzzling reflections in a mirror.
圣经
-你在干什么？ -当我们崛起的那一天...
- What are you doing? - And on the day we rise...
我们会清楚的知道并理解他的奥秘所在
we will see with clarity and understand the mystery of his ways.
我们祈祷吧
Let us pray.
这个世界上总共有3种人...
There are three types of people in this world...
羊  狼  还有牧羊犬
sheep, wolves, and sheepdogs.
有些人认为
Now, some people prefer to
邪恶是不存在于这个世界的
believe that evil doesn't exist in the world.
当邪恶降临时
And if it ever darkened their doorstep,
他们不懂得如何保护自己
they wouldn't know how to protect themselves.
这种人是羊
Those are the sheep.
然后就会出现掠食者
And then you got predators.
他们会使用暴力 掠夺弱者  他们是狼
They use violence to prey on the weak. They're the wolves.
还有一类人
And then there are those
他们身负强大的攻击力
who've been blessed with the gift of aggression
和保护羊群的天性
and the overpowering need to protect the flock.
这一类很稀有 并可以与狼对抗
These men are the rare breed that live to confront the wolf.
他们就是牧羊犬
They are the sheepdog.
我们这个家不培养羊
Now, we're not raising any sheep in this family.
如果你们变成狼 我会抽你们
And I will whup your ass if you turn into a wolf.
韦恩
Wayne.
但我们要保护好自己
But we protect our own.
如果有人想打你
Now, if someone tries to fight you
或者欺负你弟弟
or tries to bully your little brother,
我允许你去解决掉
you have my permission to finish it.
是那家伙先挑衅杰夫的
The guy was picking on Jeff.
-真的吗？ -是的 是他先动手的
- Is that true? - Yes, sir. Yes, he was.
那你解决了吗？
Did you finish it?
那你们就知道你们是谁
Well, then you know who you are.
知道你们的目标
You know your purpose.
今晚克里斯·凯尔拉着那匹叫大小姐的马来到这里
Chris Kyle is on the horse Big Mistress here this evening.
你没问题的
You're all right.
准备好了
Now, get ready.
很好
That's good.
今晚 他要冲刺最高分86分
So, tonight, he needs to beat the leading score of 86.
嘿 杰夫  你哥哥好像又赢了
Hey, Jeff. Looks like your brother did it again.
...克里斯·凯尔
...Chris Kyle.
那里又没人  你还戴着皮带扣出来
Man, wasn't nobody there. You come out with a belt buckle.
你戴它干什么？
- What are you supposed to do with it?
戴它上床
- Supposed to get laid with it.
我要戴着它 看看能否引起莎拉的兴致
I'm gonna wear it and see if it puts Sarah in the mood.
见鬼 一场大风都能让莎拉兴致勃勃
Shit, a strong wind'll put Sarah in the mood.
哦 他们是这么说的吗？
Oh, is that what they say?
你知道高中时他们怎么叫她的
Man, you know what they called her in high school.
-好了 别说了 -毒瘾莎拉...
- All right. Don't say it. - Sarah sucks-a-lotta...
-没听到我说的吗？ -见鬼 克里斯
- What'd I say? - Shit, Chris.
该死的
Goddamn it.
两个女孩都很值得花钱的  这就是为什么...
That was bucking money, those two girls. And that's why... no.
他一直盯着她
He kept looking... he had his eyes on her,
那就是为什么上次...
and that's why, the last time...
-到时你就知道了 -对
- Wait till you see what this does. - Yeah.
该我了 臭小子
That's me, you dog.
嘿 宝贝  谁想跟牛仔竞技明星上床？搞什么鬼？
Hey, baby. Who wants to fuck a rodeo star? What the fuck?
你说过明天才会回来
You said you wasn't coming home until tomorrow.
-我说什么？ -不是  我没有...
- I said what? - No, I just didn't...
克里斯 放开他 好吗？他什么也没做！
Chris, just leave him alone, all right? He didn't do anything!
-我什么也不知道 救命！ -克里斯 放开他！
- I didn't know shit, man. Help! - Chris, leave him alone!
克里斯  放开他！
Fucking Chris, leave him alone!
该死的 你怎么回事？
Goddamn it! What is wrong with you?
-他不知道 好吗？
- He didn't know, all right?
-他不知道？你不知道什么？
- Oh, he didn't know? What didn't you know?
-把帽子给我 -把帽子给他 宝贝
- Just give me my hat. - Get his hat, baby.
他不知道什么？你以为那些枪是谁的？
He didn't know what? Whose rifles did you think those were?
那些男人的衣服都是她的吗？
Those clothes, them men's clothes weren't hers?
这你都不知道吗？
Is that what you didn't know?
你他妈有什么问题？
What the fuck is wrong with you?!
那你也不用见人就打
You don't have to fucking punch everyone!
把帽子带上  快滚
Put that fucking hat on and get the fuck out.
你他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
滚走
Get out.
你知道吗？我不知道你为什么要找我
You know what? I don't know what you expect from me.
你把我扔在这里
You drag me out here and then
然后每个周末又跟你弟弟跑出去
you run off with your brother every damn weekend.
你以为我为什么要这样？
Why do you think I did this?
我这么做是想让你注意我 你不明白吗？
I do this to get attention! Don't you get that?
拿上你的东西  滚走
Get your stuff and get out.
好  去你的  我走
Fine. Fine. You know what? Fuck you. Fine.
你以为你参加了竞技 你就是牛仔了
You think you're a cowboy 'cause you rodeo.
你不是什么牛仔 你只是个肮脏的牧场工
You're not a cowboy. You're just a lousy ranch hand.
你就是个该死的王八蛋
And you're a shitty fucking lay.
别说了
Don't say it.
什么时候办婚礼？
When's the wedding?
我知道你在说什么 但是...
I understand what you're saying, but...
你知道 我们要游变整个州
you know, we get to travel over the whole state.
每个周末都去不同的城市
Different city every weekend.
与野马公牛为伴
Broncs and steers.
-我不知道 可能她是对的 -她是对的？
- I don't know. Maybe she's right, though. - She's right?
哪里对了 克里斯？她错了，我们是牛仔
Right about what, Chris? She's not right, man. We're cowboys.
-我们活在梦想中 -下面是一则特别报道
- We're living the dream. - This is a special report.
在驻达累斯萨拉姆（坦桑尼亚首都）和内罗毕（肯尼亚首都）...
Those explosions set to go off at the U.S. Embassies
美国大使馆发生了连环爆炸案
in Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, and Nairobi, Kenya,
很明显是针对美国政府及公民战斗的一环
were clearly a part of someone's war against the United States.
超过80名死者
More than 80 dead, more than
以及1700名伤者...
1,700 injured in two bomb blasts today...
嘿 杰夫 杰夫
Hey, Jeff. Jeff. Hey.
看这个
- Look at this.
目前还不清楚我们的敌人是谁
It is still unclear at this hour who our enemy is.
不过袭击目标显然是美国大使馆...
Although the embassies were obviously the targets...
-看他们对我们做了什么 -...伤者并非美国公民
- Look what they did to us. - ...and injured are not Americans.
仍然有8名美国公民包括一名儿童死亡 并有5人失踪
Still, eight Americans, including one child are dead, and five are still missing.
军队职业指导中心
-你是德克萨斯来的 -是的
- So, you're from Texas. - Yes, sir.
-你是个爱国者 -是的
- You're a patriot. - Yes, sir.
-你被惹毛了 -我想为国家效劳
- And you're pissed off. - I'm looking to be of service.
-你喜欢战斗？ -是的
- You like to fight? - Yes, sir.
你喜欢战斗 好的
You like to fight. Okay. Well...
那要不让你见见精英战士？
Why don't you meet the warrior elite?
-海豹突击队 -对 海陆空都行
- SEALs. - Yep. Sea, air, and land.
但是我水性不好
Well, I'm not much for the water, sir.
不好？我们这里不欢迎胆小鬼
No? Well, this ain't for the faint-a heart.
大多数人都被淘汰或主动退出了
Most men, they wash out, they quit.
我不是大多数人 我不会放弃
But I'm not most men, sir. I don't quit.
-各位 玩笑到此为止 -坚持住 姑娘们
- This is where the fun stops, guys! - Take it, girls! Take it!
就是这样 姑娘们 坚持住 只有第一次会痛
That's it, girls. Take it. Take it. Only hurts the first time.
-看我们这里来了什么？你是个废物吗？
- What we got here? You a quitter, boy?
报告罗尔教官 不是
- Hooyah, no, instructor Rolle.
放屁 再让我看到 就把你的屁股踢开花
Bullshit! Yo ass is fleet meat if I ever did see it!
别躲开我 小子
Don't turn away from me, son.
看着我 好好地冲一下
You look at me and you take this shit.
-是的 长官！ -该死的 你这个老混蛋！
- Hooyah, sir! - Damn, you old as fuck!
你是因为诺亚方舟上
You join the Navy 'cause you
太舒服了 才来加入海军吗？
had such a good goddamn time on Noah's ark?
-小子 你多大了？-报告 30
- How old are you, boy? - Hooyah, 30!
30？你放的屁都要比这些小子长一半
30? Your fart dust could have fathered half these boys.
我们要淘汰废物
We gonna weed through the quitters.
两天内 我们要选出我们的战士
Yeah, we gonna find us a goddamn warrior on two today.
道贝尔 你确定你是来自康尼狄格州？
Dauber, are you sure you're from Connecticut?
我还没见过哈特福德来的乡巴佬
I ain't never met no hick from Hartford before.
报告教官 我是美国人 农村的
Hooyah, instructor Friday! Country's countrywide.
来这里是为了杀恐怖分子
I came here to kill terrorists.
谁告诉你这个傻逼可以傻笑的？
Who the fuck told your ass to giggle?
罗尔教官 没有人
Hooyah, no one, instructor Rolle!
我允许你张嘴了吗
- Did I ask you to open up your mouth?
罗尔教官 没有
- Hooyah, no, instructor Rolle.
瞧瞧你的脂肪 只会傻笑
Look at your fat, pasty, giggly ass.
孩子 你就是一个大饭桶
Damn, son! You a big Dr. Pepper, cheeto-eating motherfucker.
是的这就是我要说的
Yeah. That's what I'm talking about.
大饭桶 从现在起 这就是你的名字
Biggles. That's your name from now on,
还有这是你回家的票
sunshine. And that's your ticket home.
你还在这里干什么 想成为我的队员吗
"D"! What are you still doing in my line, trying to make this team?
-所有人都知道 黑人不会游泳
- Everybody knows black guys don't swim.
是的 长官  但我不是那种黑人
- It's all right, sir. I'm not black.
-不是？ 不是 我是新一代黑人
- No? - No. I'm the new black.
我们跑的慢 跳的低 游的好 还在GAP店里买衣服
We run slow, we jump low, we swim good, and we shop at gap.
我在白人面前骄傲
And I make the white folk proud
因为我能拐走他们的女友 我们干翻他们
when I hose down their ladies. I dick 'em down!
在那里 那是个废物
There it is! That is a quitter.
你说拜拜 我就谢天谢地了
You say goodbye, I say good riddance.
他在这里放弃 将来他就会在战场上放弃
He quits on you here, he's gonna quit in the field of battle.
你等的发毛 他也不会前进一步
When shit gets hairy, he won't step up.
你中枪了 他也不会把你拖开
Your ass gets shot, he won't pull you out.
我要找的是勇士
I'm looking for warriors!
-7 -继续数
- Seven! - Keep counting!
- 8 9 -我听不见
- Eight! Nine! - I can't hear you!
你想让我打电话给你妈妈吗 老家伙？
You want me to call your mama, old man?
也许她来都做的比你好
Maybe she could come and take your place.
这是前戏
This is foreplay!
我要来点马文的音乐 你们就照着节奏来
I'm about to turn on some Marvin Gaye and get in that ass!
没错 就是这个意思
That's what I'm talking about!
小兵们 你们的蛋蛋在哪里？
Squirrel, Squirrel, Squirrel, where the fuck are your nuts?
它们一切安好 长官 它们缩回到了身体里
Oh, they're gone for good, sir. They crawled back up inside.
但他们很温暖
But they are warm.
小鬼讲大话
Big talk from a little man!
老家伙 你呢？
Now you. How about you, old man?
感觉如何？
How you feeling?
报告 危险 我感觉很危险
Hooyah, dangerous. Feeling dangerous.
是吗 凯尔感觉有危险
Hooyah! Kyle's feeling dangerous.
行动
Move!
坐下
Take seats!
56度角 如此新鲜 如此干净
Damn! 56 degrees, so fresh, so clean.
再坚持几个小时 你们就是海豹突击队员了
Only a few more hours, and you're Navy SEALs!
-我是唯一击中目标的 所以... -是的
- I'm the only one who's hit one, so... - Yeah.
嘣
Boom!
-噢 厉害 -克里斯 该你了
- Oh, yeah. - Chris, your turn, man.
-不 你还得来一次 -还有一次？好吧
- No, you got one more. - I got one more? All right.
好吧 再来一次 准备好 开始
All right. One more. Here we go. Here we go.
嘿 我们需要小一点的目标 就用你的胳膊吧 伙计
Hey, we want a smaller target, we'll use your arm, man.
-你好 -嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
还好吗？
How you doing?
很好 谢谢
Good. Thank you.
我能请你一杯酒吗？
Can I... get you a drink?
一杯酒就能让你长高 而且变得有魅力吗？
Will a drink make you six inches taller and charming?
-能让你变成未婚吗？ -我不是...
- Will it make you not married? - I'm not...
是吗 我刚看见你把戒指摘下来 好吗？
Yeah. I just watched you take your ring off, okay?
别当个无赖 回家吧
Don't be a scumbag. Go home.
噢 老天
Oh, my God.
-可能是皮裤的原因 -噢 是吗？
- It may have been the leather pants. - Oh, yeah?
女孩要穿什么裤子 才能免于骚扰？
What kind of pants does a girl have to wear to be left alone?
灯芯绒裤也许可以
Well, maybe corduroy.
我说 你们这类人就是这样的吗？
I mean, is that how it is with you guys?
喝三杯啤酒 就突然变回单身了？
You're, like, suddenly single after three beers?
噢 不  三杯啤酒后 我能想到的是再来第四杯
Oh, no. After three beers, all I know is to get a fourth.
噢 不错  很好  真正的乡巴佬
Oh, that's great. That's great. Real redneck.
我不是乡巴佬 我是德州来的
Oh, I'm not a redneck. I'm from Texas.
有什么区别？
What's the difference?
区别就是 我们骑马 他们一家人互相骑
Well, we ride horses and they ride their cousins.
你是做什么的 很明显你是个军人
What do you do for work? You're obviously military.
我是给圈养的海豚洗澡的
I polish dolphins. They're in captivity.
把它们身上的脏东西都擦掉
What I do is just sort of scrape off the crustaceans.
-在你眼里我看起来很蠢吗？ 不是 实话说 你看起来有点悲伤
- Do I look stupid to you? - No. Honestly, you look a little sad.
我够高可以请你喝一杯酒吗？
- Am I... tall enough to buy you a drink?
除非你能告诉我你是做什么的
- Not until you tell me what you do.
好吧 这样如何 嘿 格雷格？
Okay. How about this? Hey, Greg?
拿两杯过来 一个问题 一杯酒
Get two shots. How 'bout we do a shot for a question?
你每问我一个问题 我回答了你就干一杯 同样反之亦然
Every time you ask me a question and I answer, you got to do a shot. Same, vice versa.
游戏开始
Game on.
这瓶酒就放这里吧 好的 开始
You can leave the bottle, too. Okay, shoot.
好的 你是军人 那个部队的？
All right. You're obviously military. What branch?
我刚完成海豹基本训练  即将接受狙击手训练
I just finished BUD/S, heading to sniper school.
-你在开玩笑嘛 你是海豹突击队的？ -是的 女士
- Are you kidding me? You're a SEAL? - Yes, ma'am.
-那是两个问题了 -该死的
- That's two questions. - Shit.
真的吗？
Really?
噢 你没必要真喝掉的
Oh, I didn't really mean you had to do that.
好吧 该死的
Okay. Shit.
我知道你们这些人 我姐姐以前和一个海豹突击队员订婚了
I know all about you guys. My sister was engaged to a SEAL.
-噢 是吗 -是的
- Oh, was she? - Yeah.
等下 你怎么那么了解我们的 你是什么意思？
Hold on. How you know all about us? What do you mean?
我想说的是 你们是一群自命不凡
What I mean is, you're a bunch of arrogant,
自我中心的混蛋 然后觉得自己可以
self-centered pricks who think you can lie
随便劈腿 想干什么就干什么 我绝对不会和海豹突击队的约会
and cheat and do whatever the fuck you want. I'd never date a SEAL.
等下 为什么你认为我会自私？
Wait. Why would you say I'm self-centered?
我都是会为国捐躯的人了
I'd lay down my life for my country.
为什么？
Why?
因为这是地球上最伟大的国家
'Cause it's the greatest country on earth,
我愿意尽我所能去保护它
and I'd do everything I can to protect it.
听着 发生在你姐姐身上的事 我感到很抱歉 但那不是我
Look, I'm sorry what happened to your sister, but that's not me.
-很高兴认识你 -你去哪？
- It's nice to meet you. - Where are you going?
我要回家
Well, I was just gonna go home
因为你说了 不跟海豹突击队的约会 所以...
because you said you wouldn't date a SEAL, so...
我说我不会嫁给他们而已
I said I'd never marry one.
噢 好吧 那么 也许...
Oh, okay. Well, then maybe,
你好 很高兴认识你 你叫什么名字？
hello. Nice to meet you. What's your name?
-塔雅 -塔雅
- Taya. - Taya.
我叫克里斯·凯尔 很高兴认识你 荣幸至极
Chris. I'm Chris Kyle. Nice to meet you. Pleasure.
你认为 你能保护我们所有人 这一点很自大 不是吗 克里斯
I mean, it's pretty egotistical of you to think you can protect us all. Isn't it, Chris?
我们的基地指挥官说 有三样...
Well, our BUD/S officer commander said that it's three...
好吧 他说有三样东西我们需要注意的:自负  酒 和女人
Okay. He said there's three things we got to worry about: Ego, booze, and women.
听起来 你好像中招了
Well, sounds like you're under attack.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
你很可爱
You're so cute.
没事的
I got you.
我不会跟你回家 所以想都别想
I'm not going home with you, so don't even think about it.
感觉呼吸 充满你身体的每一个细胞
Feel breath filling every cell in your body.
这是我们的仪式
This is our ritual.
要会控制呼吸 控制自己的头脑
We master our breath, we master our mind.
扣动扳机将会成为一种无意识行为
Pulling the trigger will become an unconscious effort.
你能意识到它 但不能引导它
You will be aware of it, but not directing it.
当你呼气时 你能感觉到你的呼吸暂停
And as you exhale, find your natural respiratory pause
和你心跳的间隔
and the space between heartbeats.
嘿 我是塔雅 我无法接听电话
Hey. This is Taya. I can't get to the phone.
请留言 我会打给你的
Leave a message. I'll call you back.
嘿 又是我 你吐我一鞋的那个家伙
Hey, it's me again. The guy whose shoes you puked on.
那么 我在想也许你没有收到 我前面发的消息
So... yeah, I was thinking maybe you didn't get that last message,
我前面发的消息 或者...
the last message I left, or...
更早之前发的消息 所以我在想...
the one before that. So I figured that...
-你在想什么？ 嘿 你好吗 过得怎么样？
- You figured what? - Hey. How are you? How've you been?
很好
Good.
很好 最近忙吗？
Good. Wow. What are you up to?
不是很忙 你呢？
Not a lot. You?
不忙 只是想和你说话
No, just... excited to talk to you.
瞄准目标越小 失误越小
Aim small, miss small.
如果你想要瞄准一颗纽扣 你可能就射偏两英寸
If you aim for a shirt button, you might miss by 2 inches.
如果你想要瞄准他的衬衫 可能就会射偏2英尺
If you aim for his shirt, you might miss by 2 feet.
-你最好能击中同一个点 -好的 长官
- You better close those groupings, Kyle. - Yes, sir.
老天
God.
-还不错 能赢什么东西？ -头奖
- Not bad. What do we get for that? - Top shelf.
-我喜欢那个 棕色的那个 -好的 没问题
- I like that one. Brown one. - Sure. Here you go.
-太好了 谢谢你 祝你愉快 -噢 瞧啊 谢谢
- Great. Thank you, sir. Have a good day. - Oh, look! Thank you.
-你好 -噢 很好 你抱着看起来不错
- Hello. - Oh, good. That looks good on you.
那么 你一直都梦想成为军人吗
So, did you always want to be a soldier?
没有 我曾经想成为一个牛仔 但是...
No. I wanted to be a cowboy, but...
我不知道  我成牛仔后 我想我应该做些更有意义的事
I don't know. I did that. Thought I was meant for something more.
所以你就开始在酒吧里拯救妹子了
So you started rescuing girls from bars?
我觉得我把你从那酒吧里拯救出来了
I think I rescued that bar from you.
-你喜欢乡村音乐吗？ -只有在我沮丧时喜欢
- You like country music? - Only when I'm depressed.
-那孩子呢？你想要孩子吗？ -也许某一天吧
- How about kids? You want kids? - Yeah, someday.
我妈妈说我总是遇上错误的人
My mom says I have a nose for picking the wrong men.
这不是该对一个女孩说的话
Well, that's a shitty thing to say to a girl.
这个 我已经证明了她说的是对的了
Well, I've proven her right.
那些错误的经历塑造了...
Them wrong picks put you here,
现在的你  我喜欢现在的你
made you who you are. I like who you are.
你有想过 当你的枪口指向一个活生生的人时 会是怎样的吗
You ever think about what happens when there's a real person on the end of that gun?
我不知道 我只希望那天来临之时 我能做好我的工作
I don't know. I just hope I can do my job when that day comes.
我们看的是同一个目标吗？你在射沙子啊
Are we looking at the same target? You're spitting dust.
别担心  那些不会射击的人 可以当医护兵
And don't worry. We can always use corpsmen for the guys who can't shoot.
操
Oh, fuck.
-你在发抖 -我知道
- You're trembling. - I know it.
-如果你不愿意我们可以不做... -不 我想要 我想要
- We don't have to do this if you don't... - No, I want to. I do.
-真的吗？ 你让我感觉很真实 吓到我了
- Yeah? - You just feel real and it scares me.
你左眼闭了吗
You got your off-eye shut?
如果我左眼闭上了 那我就看不到外面什么情况了
Well, if I close my off-eye, then I can't see what's out there.
外面除了目标 什么都没有
- There's nothing out there but the target.
不 长官  那里有什么东西
- Negative. Sir, there is something out there.
那打它啊
Punch it.
俯卧撑有用吗？来50个 凯尔 要打就打吧
Will push-ups help? Give me 50, Kyle. Clear and safe.
我比较会打活的东西
I'm better when it's breathing.
-...看似是另一个... -噢 老天 克里斯
- ...what appears to be another... - Oh, my God. Chris!
-怎么了？ -不
- What's wrong? - No!
这是录像 第一架飞机看起来像是从东面飞过来的
Here's the tape. You see the first plane coming in from what looks like the east side.
冒着浓烟撞进大楼
And it goes into the building with the flames
浓烟从塔楼的另一侧翻滚而出
and the smoke billowing out the other side of the tower.
很难确定 哪里是北面 哪里是南面
It's hard for me to tell exactly which is the north side and which is the south side.
但它好像是从北边出现了
But it appears it's coming out of the north side there.
然后片刻之前 难以置信的事情发生了
And then, moments ago, these incredible images.
我认为这是第一架
I believe that's the first one.
南塔正在坍塌
That's the south tower collapsing.
现在你们看到的像是建筑的一次内部破裂...
It almost looks like one of those implosions of buildings that you see,
一切都已经失控
except there is nothing
破灭是巨大的
controlled about this. This is devastation.
你甚至都不了解我
You don't even know me.
我足够了解你 宝贝 你是一个很好的女人
I know enough. You are a package deal, babe.
-你害怕什么呢？ -没什么
- What are you so afraid of? - Nothing.
所有事吧 我不知道  万一合不来怎么办？
Everything. I don't know. What if it doesn't work out?
我们会结婚然后组建一个家庭
We're gonna get married and then we're gonna start a family.
你都计划好了 是吗？
You got it all planned out, don't you?
是的
I'm done.
我爱你
I love you.
如果你这样和我说话 是需要一枚戒指的
Well, you're gonna need a ring if you want to talk all tough like that.
好的
Okay.
女士们先生们 欢迎克里斯·凯尔夫妇
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. And Mrs. Chris Kyle!
你脖子上是什么？
What the hell is on your neck?
你的脖子 好像你全身都变绿了
Your neck. You've got, like, green paint all over you.
宝贝 如果我告诉你 我刚打了针
Would you believe me, babe, if I told you I had an I.V.
两小时之前就已经浑身发绿了 你会信吗？
and I was all green about two hours ago?
你说...什么？
What are you... what?
-你已经逃不掉了 宝贝 -噢 老天
- It's a package deal, babe. - Oh, my God.
来吧
Come here, you.
恭喜了
Cheers to that.
怎么说 头儿？
What's the word, chief?
小子们 刚收到消息 开始了
Just got the call, boys. It's on!
干杯
Shots!
太棒了
Yes!
来五杯
Five shots.
真好
Yeah!
-宝贝 只要去六个星期 -我很害怕 宝贝
- It's only gonna be six weeks, baby. - I'm so afraid, baby.
他们都是这么说的 你不必害怕
That's what they say. You got nothing to be afraid of.
-你... -这都是计划中的
- What are you... - It's all part of the plan.
你的心脏都快从胸腔里跳出来了
Your heart is beating out of your chest.
那是因为我不是唯一走上战场的人 仅此而已
That's just 'cause I'm not the only one that's going to war. That's all.
干杯！
Cheers!
第一次行军
欢迎来到法鲁贾 古老中东里的"新狂野西部"
Welcome to Fallujah. The new wild west of the old Middle East.
基地组织悬赏了你们脑袋
AQI put a price on your heads,
现在全世界的极端分子
and now extremists from around the globe
为了赏金蜂拥而至 你们狙击手...
are flooding the borders to collect on it. You snipers...
会分配一名海军陆战队员做搭档
you're gonna be paired with a marine
他会负责保护你的后方 然后你们驻守主干道
to watch your back and inserted along the main road
为海军陆战一队的搜查掩护
to do overwatch for 1st marines going door to door.
你们的任务是不惜一切代价保护那些陆战队员
Your job is to protect those marines at all costs.
所有市民都已经撤离了
This city has been evacuated.
任何在这里的可疑作战人员都是为了杀你而留下的
Any military-age male who is still here... is here to kill you.
让我们保证这些伙计的安全吧 然后我们一起平安回家
Let's bring these boys in safe and get our asses back home.
都下车 快 快
Out, out, out!
我会一直低着头的 德州小子
I'd keep that head down, Tex.
对方也有狙击手
Muj got snipers, too, you know.
狙击手是不会瞄准你的头部的
A sniper won't aim for your head.
老兄 他们有一个狙击手
Man, they got this one sniper
可以在500码以外 打中你的头
that's been hitting head shots from 500 yards out.
他们叫他穆斯塔法
They call him Mustafa.
他是奥林匹克选手
He's in the Olympics.
奥林匹克还有狙击项目了
They got sniping in the Olympics now?
等等  我看到一个女人带着孩子
Hold on. I got a woman and a kid,
200码远  正往车队方向走去
200 yards out, moving towards the convoy.
她的手臂没有摆动  她带着一些东西
Her arms aren't swinging. She's carrying something.
她拿了一个手榴弹
She's got a grenade.
她刚刚把一个俄制RKG手榴弹给了那个小孩
She's got an RKG Russian grenade she just handed to the kid.
你是说一个女人和一个小孩？
You say a woman and a kid?
你看见了？确定吗？
- You got eyes on this? Can you confirm?
没有  你知道交战规则  你来决定
- Negative. You know the R.O.E. Your call.
如果你搞错了 他们会炒了你
Man, they fry you if you're wrong.
然后一脚把你踢到莱文沃思
They send your ass to Leavenworth.
操 看不下去了
Fuck, that was gnarly.
他妈的婊子
Fucking evil bitch.
起来 继续前进
Get up. Keep moving.
打得漂亮 德州小子 判断很准确
- Nice shooting, Tex. Hell of a call.
收到 警戒做的不错 海军
- Roger that. Good looking out, Navy.
-老兄 你听到了吗？ -别碰我
- Fuck, did you hear that, man? - Get the fuck off me.
大伙人呢？
Where is everybody?
我们在这里呢
We're just checking our dicks here,man.
在训练这些 该死的伊斯兰士兵
We're training those fucking Hajji soldiers.
嘿 你为什么不去呢
Yeah, why aren't you out there?
-因为我有事 -什么 看漫画书吗？
- Well, I have the shits. - What, reading a comic book?
这他妈是图绘小说 区别很大
It's a fucking graphic novel, man. There's a big difference.
我听说你在那边开火了
I heard you were on fucking fire out there.
马克·李来过 说你破了处 开了第一枪 是吗
Marc Lee came in, said you popped your cherry. Is that right?
有一个毛都没长齐的孩子
There was a kid who... barely had any hair on his balls.
他妈妈给了他一颗手雷
Mother gives him a grenade,
就派他去炸陆战队了
sends him out there to kill marines.
我以前从没见过这么罪恶的事
Dude, that's evil like I never seen before.
是啊 但是
Yeah. But, hey, man,
你知道那个孩子可能会干掉十个陆战队员 对吧
you know that kid could have taken out like 10 fucking marines, right?
是啊 但我杀了他
Yeah, but I killed him.
你做了你该做的 就这样了
You did your job. That's the end of the story.
是啊 只是我没想到 我干掉的第一个目标是个孩子
Yeah, it's just not how I envisioned that first one to go down.
莱利 没事的 确实没有看到
Riley, it's okay. Don't have the actuals.
他妈的 什么情况
Fuck, man! What the hell?
你就是掩护的 爱因斯坦 你可以等会感谢他
That was your overwatch, Einstein. You can thank him later.
我们走
Let's move!
继续前进
Keep going.
快
Hurry up.
全部散开
Disperse!
停火！停火！
Cease fire! Cease fire!
注意屋顶 看着上面
Eyes on the rooftop! Keep your eyes up there!
有人受伤 需要医护兵
Man down! Man down! We need a corpsman over here now!
定位地方狙击手 大致坐标QR 155604
Enemy sniper located. Approximate grid, Quebec-Romeo,1-5-5-6-0-4.
-这里闻着一股尿骚味 -嗯...
- Smells like piss in here. - Yeah, well...
是你掩护我们到那里的  打的很有种
You covered our asses out there, man. Some ballsy shots.
-该死的 他们很安全 对吧 -是啊
- Fuck. They were clean, right? - Hell yeah, they were.
那狙击手就在我们的后面
That fucking sniper went right up our ass!
我已经把安全细节检查了一遍
Yeah, I already chewed out security detail.
这事不会再发生了
It ain't gonna happen again.
最好别再发生
It better not happen again.
-400米外有个热点 -好的
- There's a hot spot 400 meters out. - All right.
我要去续写神射手的光辉了
I'm gonna go write up some shooter statements.
-你干掉了多少个？ -我干掉了6个...噢 不对
- How many'd you get? - I got six... oh. No, that's not true.
是8个 但是他们说有两个不算
I got eight, but they dragged two off.
-你干了6个？ -是的 怎么了？
- You got six? - Yeah. Why? What's wrong?
没什么 你干掉的人数 比其他狙击手总和还要多
Nothing. You just got more than the rest of the snipers combined.
是啊 但他们也打中了我们一个
- Yeah, but they got one of us.
你看不到就无法射击
- You can't shoot what you can't see.
他妻子说他拿着本《古兰经》
His wife said he was carrying a Koran.
听着 我不知道《古兰经》是什么样的
Look, I don't know what a Koran looks like,
但我能告诉你他拿着什么
but I can tell you what he was carrying.
压制金属做的 口径7.62
It was pressed metal, shot 7.62s,
看起来像是AK-47
and it looked just like an AK-47.
所以你告诉我他拿着什么
So you tell me what he was carrying.
噢 他来了 他来了
Oh, here he comes. Here he comes.
女士们先生们 请注意 我们这里出现了以为传奇
Ladies and genitals, listen up! We have a legend in our midst!
为传奇欢呼喝彩吧
Round of applause for The Legend!
来吧 欢迎你回来 我们为你骄傲 伙计
There we go. We're so proud of you back home on the range, boy.
据说...这位传奇人物...
Now, it's been... it's been said that The Legend here
一口气能干掉100个人
can kill 100 men with one blow.
或者...怎么说来着...
Or, no, it was... what was... nah, it was... fuck. What was it?
一个人...只需要一口气 他就能干掉100人
It was one... one blow from a single man. He blew 100... men.
而他只身一人...该死的
And he's single. And... Goddamn it! Shit!
哦 见鬼
Oh, shit!
-混蛋 -可恶
- Damn, man. - Oh, fuck.
你想要丢食大战吗 来吧
You want a food fight? Come on.
-可恶 -只有这样才能让你闭嘴
- Shit. - Only way to shut you up.
你杀过人吗？
Have you killed anyone yet?
打电话回家不应该说这样的话嘛 宝贝
That is not the way the call home is supposed to go, babe.
不要怪我 说真的
Don't be weird with me. Seriously.
我希望你能把一切都告诉我
I want you to tell me everything.
有些事在电话里是不能说的
Well, there's certain things you just can't say over the phone.
好吧 你让我大肚子了 好吗
Okay, you knocked me up, right?
我自己坐在这里 组装婴儿床
And I'm sitting here by myself literally assembling baby cribs,
然后你却说不能说？这就是你的伟大计划？
and you can't talk to me? That's your big plan?
你们的任务快结束了 是吗？
You guys almost done over there yet?
我不停的回想蜜月时你穿的那件粉色数字衣服
I can't stop thinking about that little pink number you wore on our honeymoon.
那叫睡衣
Yeah, it's called a nightgown.
是啊
Yeah.
还有...3天..
And three days...
3天不能叫做蜜月
three days is not a honeymoon.
可是 那也是美好的三天啊
Well, it was a good three days.
我真的很想你
I miss you real bad.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
-嘿 想听我说一些下流的话吗 -好啊
- Hey, you want me to talk dirty to you? - Yeah.
等下 等一下 我...
Hold on. Hold on a second. Let me just...
我一手拿着电话 一手拿着枪
I got... A phone in one hand and a gun in the other,
真不知道要怎么办了
so I don't know what I'm gonna do.
那要你自己决定哪个更重要了 宝贝
Well, you're gonna have to decide what's more important, baby.
噢 你这淫荡的小孕妇
Oh, you're a horny preggers.
又骚又胖 听起来就恶心
Fat and horny. It's fucking disgusting.
就算你300磅重 我也爱你
If you were 300 pounds, I'd still do you.
真浪漫
So romantic.
-我儿子如何了？ -谁告诉你是男孩了
- How's my boy? - Nobody said it's a boy.
我等不及看到你和他的样子了
I can't wait to see the way you're gonna be with him.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我就是知道
I just know.
我能感觉到
I can sense it.
-希望你是对的 -宝贝 我就是对的
- I hope you're right. - Baby, I am right.
美军在伊拉克死亡人数
8月        66人
你爸爸联系你了吗
- Hey, did your dad get ahold of you?
我还没看我的电子邮件
- I haven't checked my e-mails.
该死的 好吧 你得把电话挂了打给他 好吗？
Shit! Okay, you need to hang up and call him, all right?
-为什么？怎么了？ -该死的
- Why? What's wrong? - Fuck.
我真自私 我都没想到
I'm so selfish. I wasn't even thinking.
塔雅 怎么了 发生什么事了？
Taya, what's wrong? What happened?
你弟弟入伍了
Your little brother deployed.
你说什么？他不是在上学吗？
What do you mean? What happened to jump school?
不 他没考上 你马上挂电话 打给你爸爸 好吗
No, he didn't get in. You just hang up and call your dad, okay?
等下 你说什么 入伍了？他在哪里？
Wait. What do you mean? Deployed where? Where is he?
在那里
Over there.
他去伊拉克了
He's headed to Iraq.
抱歉 亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
拿着刀的那个人 是个约旦的武装分子
The man with the blade, he's a Jordanian militant.
他有本拉登的支持  本拉登亲自训练他
He's funded by Bin Laden. He's trained by Bin Laden.
他对其也十分忠心
He is loyal to Bin Laden.
他叫扎卡维
His name is Zarqawi.
那么这个混蛋是基地组织的继承人
Now, this asshole is right now the crown prince of Al-Qaeda in Iraq.
他的雇佣军 基地组织 有5000人
His mercenary army, AQI, they're 5,000 strong.
这些家伙不是普通货色
Now, these guys are not your average shit-kickers.
他们训练有素 待遇优厚
These guys are well trained, they are well paid.
而现在 他们正在掀起自越南战争以来最大的内战
And right now, they are waging the largest urban assault since Vietnam.
扎卡维和他的副官们是我们的首要目标
Zarqawi and his lieutenants, these are our top priority.
要把他们连根拔起 只有一个办法
Now, there is only one way to root these guys out,
就是挨家挨户的搜查
and that is to go door to door, house to house,
直到我们找到他们
until we find them or we
或者能提供他们所在地点的人
find someone who will give us their whereabouts.
所以 我们要在一个小时里清查10栋建筑
So, we are going to need to clear 10 structures an hour,
我知道 任务很重 很有侵略性
which, I know, is a lot. It's aggressive.
我们要为空中支援做好一切准备工作
We're gonna be loosening things up with air support.
这是我们的最高目标
This is the highest priority target we have to date.
我要这个混蛋要么被击毙 要么被俘虏  明白吗？
I want this asshole dead or captured. Do you understand?
有问题吗？
Are there any questions?
我跟你说
I'll tell you something.
这些陆战队员要是像之前那样冲
These marines keep rushing in like they're doing,
他们就等着屁股开花吧
- they're gonna have their asses shot off.
他们是陆战队的
- Well, they're marines.
不想我们这样训练有素
They don't get the training we do.
六个月前这里有一半人还是普通公民
Half these guys were civilians six months ago.
那么把他们组织起来  我会告诉他们 我们队员是怎么做的
Well, let's coach them up. I'll show them how team guys do it.
然后我来带队
- I'll lead the unit on the street.
不 不能那样做  我们需要你掩护行动
- No, can't do that. We need you on overwatch.
别这样 如果我在街上 马克...
Oh, come on. If I'm on the street, Marc, I could...
挨家搜查是死亡率最高的任务
House-to-house is the deadliest job here.
你是不是有救世主情节？
You got some sort of savior complex?
不是  我只是想专注坏人
No, I just want to get the bad guys.
但如果我看不见他们 我就没法射中他们
But if I can't see them, I can't shoot them.
听着 所有的这些人 他们知道你的名字
Look, all these guys, they know your name.
当你在上面 他们会感到无所不能
And they feel invincible with you up there.
-才不是 -如果他们那么想 那就会
- They're not. - They are if they think they are.
你为什么不赶紧抓紧你的长枪？
Why don't you keep banging on the long gun?
让这些猎犬去把扎卡维找出来
We'll let these dogs sniff out Zarqawi.
你说基地组织有个狙击手去了奥运会？
You said AQI has a sniper in the Olympics,
但是伊拉克在三场比赛里 没有一个合格的
but Iraq hasn't qualified a shooter in three games.
那是因为穆斯塔法不是伊拉克人
Well, that's 'cause Mustafa's not Iraqi.
他是叙利亚的
He's from Syria.
重整队伍！
Regroup!
嘿 一旦你们进去了 我就看不到了
Hey, once you all gain entry, I can't see shit.
所以小心一点 慢慢移动
So take it slow and move through your target.
-明白 -小心爆炸
- Understood. - Fire in the hole!
快 行动
Go, go, go!
该死的
Fuck this.
我要和陆战队一起搜查这些房子
I'm gonna go clear houses with marines.
-你来吗？ -他妈的我才不去呢
- You coming? - Fuck no, I'm not coming.
老兄 我热爱生命 我想活着回家
No, man. I like my life. I'd actually like to make it home alive.
听着 挨家搜查不是我的工作  知道嘛
Look, it's not my job to go fucking knocking down doors, all right?
这些家伙选错了活  我才不会干这种狗屎事儿
Those guys picked the wrong fucking job. I'm not doing that shit.
好吧 如果我没在下面看到你...
All right, well, if I don't see you down there,
以后也不用再看见你了
you make sure I don't see you again.
嘿 介意我跟你们一起行动吗
Hey. Y'all mind if I roll with you?
嘿 兄弟  任何海豹突击队员和我在一起都好
Hey, man. Any SEAL is cool by me.
你是那个被他们称作传奇的人
You're that guy, the one they're calling The Legend.
你已经击毙24人了
You got like 24 confirmed kills.
-谁数的？-太他妈的酷了
- Well, who's counting? - That's fucking bad-ass.
我听到有个混球在为你喝彩
Yeah, I heard some motherfucker in Bravo's catching up, yo.
听着 我知道你们都是肉食动物
Listen. I know y'all are meat-eaters,
但有些事 我先告诉你们
for sure, but I know a couple things,
也许这些简单的东西可以让我们活下来 怎么样？
some simple shit I could show you. Maybe keep us above ground. What do you say?
-好 -好的
- Yeah. - All right.
好极了
Right on.
-嘿 那是什么意思 老兄？ -把门砸开
- Hey, what's that mean, bro? - Breacher up.
-行动 -趴下 趴地上
- Moving. - Get down! Get down on the ground right now!
给我趴地上！ -不不
- Get your fucking ass down! - No, no!
-他听不懂 -趴下
- He no understand! - Get down!
你为什么还在这里？
Why are you here?
你应该已经撤离这里了 为什么还在这里？
You're supposed to be evacuating this area. Why are you still here?
我是酋长
- I am Sheikh Al-Obeidi.
什么酋长？你到底是谁？
- Sheik Alla-who?! Who the fuck are you?!
-这是我家 我留在这里 -我不管这是不是你家
- This is my home! I stay! - I don't give a fuck it's your home!
-这里是战区 -先生 拜托！
- This is a war zone, sir! - Sir, please!
-让那个孩子趴下 -不不
- Get that kid down! - No! No!
你 先生  让我帮你
- You, sir. Let me help you.
在后面衣橱里发现了这些婊子
- Found these bitches in the back closet.
欢迎你来到这里 你们是我的客人
You are welcome here. You are my guest.
这里还有多少人？
- How many more you have here?!
告诉士兵进来
- But tell the soldiers to come in.
不 这个伊斯兰教徒想让我们都进来 这样就可以把我们炸上天了
No. This Hajji just wants us all in here so he can blow us up.
去看他的屁股里有没有...
- Go check his ass for a...
如果他见到美国人 他就知道我们有过谈话
- If he see American, he know we speak.
谁？ 谁看到你跟我们说话了？
- Who? Who? Who saw you talking to us?
这太危险了 拜托进来吧
- It's very dangerous. Please come in.
-谁知道我们跟你聊过 -他来了
- Who knows we're talking to you? Who?! - He come. He come.
他...他来...
He... he come. He...
非常坏 拜托
Very bad. Please.
-目标安全吗 -安全
- This target's secure? - Target secure.
把他们带过来 趴地上
Bring them in. Get your head down on the ground.
双手背后
Put your hands behind your back.
快  快一点
Now! Move now!
-拜托 -你如果说话 我们会跟你谈的
- Please! Please! - You talk, we'll talk to you.
把他带到另外一个房间
Bring him in the other room.
如果他和美军说话
If he talks to U.S. Soldiers,
他们就会去他家 杀了他们家人 以一儆百
they will come to his house and make examples of them.
他？ 他是谁？
He? Who's he? Who's he?
人们都称他为"屠夫"
The man who comes, they call "The Butcher."
它会带来绝望
He's the despaired one.
撒旦之子...恶魔之子
Son of Shaytan, son of... son of devil.
噢 就像执行人？
Oh, he's like an enforcer?
是的 执行人
Yes, enforcer.
-头号战士 扎卡维  -扎卡维？
- Number-one soldier Zarqawi. - Zarqawi?
-扎卡维 -我们想知道他在哪
- Zarqawi. - Yeah, we'd like to know where Zarqawi is.
你知道他在哪吗？马上告诉我他的地点
You know where he is? You tell us where he is right now.
我们怎么呢抓住他
How can we get him?
你有扎卡维的消息 马上告诉我们
Do you have information for us about Zarqawi? Tell us right now.
你找到屠夫 你就找到扎卡维 他是扎卡维的下属
You find the Butcher, you find Zarqawi. He reports to him.
好的 那怎么找到他呢？
Okay, well, how do we find him?
好吧 我跟你说话的时候你要看着我 我们去哪找他？
All right, look at me when I'm talking to you. Where do we find him?
我们必须理解 他们这样做的风险 他想要钱
We must understand the risk to them, but he will ask for money.
-10万美元 -你要10万美元
- $100,000. - You need $100,000?
我没有证据证明有这个人
I have no proof this guy exists.
法蒂玛
Fatima!
你好
Howdy.
Hello.
这就是证据
This is the proof.
听着 我也想帮你
All right, look, I wanna help you out.
我想 但是我需要一些信息
I do. But I need something.
我需要电话号码 地址 姓名 你得告诉我一些情报
I need phone numbers, address, names. You have to give me something.
-长官 第一排收到阻拦  -我们走
- Sir. First platoon's pinned down. - Let's move out!
酋长 我跟你讲话的时候看着我
Sheikh, look at me when I'm talking to you.
嘿 看着我 我需要情报
Hey! Look at me! I need something.
我可以帮助你 酋长
I can help you out, Sheikh.
给我名字 我们会处理好一切的
You give me a name, and we will take care of it.
我向你保证 我们会保护你的
I can promise you that. We will give you safety.
-想在就告诉我！ -埃米尔·阿纳法努斯
- Tell me right now! - Amir Khalaf Fanus!
-埃米尔·阿纳法努斯？ -埃米尔·卡拉夫·费奴什
- Emile Anafanoos? - Amir Khalaf Fanus.
这是屠夫的名字
This is the given name of the Butcher.
我们认为屠夫是扎卡维的二号人物
We believe that the Butcher is Zarqawi's number two man.
这就是你要的人
This is your guy right here.
但你不知道他的真名
Yeah, but you don't know his real name.
否则 你会把它写在那里
Otherwise, you'd have written it up there.
我们有几个别名
We got several aliases.
如果"费奴什"存在...
Now, if "Fanus" Is legit...
-我们...回去见下酋长 -他要10万块
- We'll... we'll go see the Sheikh. - He's asking for 100,000.
10万美元 如果它交出屠夫信息 他就会得到这些钱
Figures. But if he delivers the Butcher, he's gonna get it.
我是特工斯尼德 国防情报局
This is agent Snead, DIA.
我需要查查埃米尔·卡拉夫·费奴什
I need a name check on an Amir Khalaf Fanus.
好的 我等着
Yeah, I'll wait.
如果我们要回到那 第三队可以拉响安全警报
If we're gonna go back out there, team 3 can pull security.
但这是不可能的
That's not gonna happen. Head shed's
如果我们携款 上面会要承包商也介入的
gonna want contractors on it if we're humping money.
嗯 我还在 找到了什么？
Yeah, I'm here. What do you got?
好的 行
All right. Okay.
我们去见下酋长阿布
Let's go see the Sheikh.
压死小动物了
Roadkill.
你知道屠夫是扎卡维的二把手吗
You know the Butcher is Zarqawi's enforcer?
人们说他的武器是钻头
They say his weapon of choice is a fucking drill.
在我加入海军前 我进了神学院
Went to seminary school before I joined the Navy.
很快就要当上牧师了
Was close to being a preacher.
那为什么没有当呢？
And why didn't you?
我喜欢赌博
I love to gamble, man.
我喜欢骰子
Love those dice.
这才是我爱的牧师
That's my kind of preacher.
电话这么多
It's like that now?
噢 你没听说吗 我是传奇
Oh, haven't you heard? I'm The Legend.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, babe.
你说的没错 医生说是男孩
You were right. The doctor says it's a boy.
什么？
What?
是男孩！
It's a boy!
是男孩
It's a boy?!
太好了 恭喜你
Hell, yeah, man. Congratulations!
克里斯
Chris?!
拿着钱 去卡车那边
Grab the money! Get to the drop!
快 拿着包 拿着包
Go! Go! Grab the bag! Grab the bag!
克里斯
Chris!
走 走 离开这里  我们一会再回来
Go! Go! Get the fuck outta here! We'll come back for them.
宝贝
Baby?
-我听到枪声了 -查查看
- I heard one shot. - Check.
看看是哪个角度打来的 大概300码的距离
Came in at an angle. Be 300 or more yards out.
老天啊
Oh, my God.
-你看到他了吗？ -我有一个很小的观察窗口
- You got a bead on him? - I got a tiny little window.
该死的 我看到屠夫了
Shit! I got eyes on the Butcher.
他在大街上抓住了酋长的孩子
He's got the Sheikh's kid on the avenue.
请求快速反应部队
Requesting QRF.
我们被狙击火力压制正在接近重要目标
We're being pinned down by sniper fire on approach of high value target.
坐标04536236 完毕
Grid 04536236. Over.
我要放烟雾弹
I wanna pop a smoke 'em and
来清楚这座建筑 然后到楼顶
secure this building. I'm going to the roof.
等下
Hold up!
-等下 -等等
- Hold. - Holding.
上
Go!
老天 我的天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
你和他们说话就和他们一起死
快点 你他妈的混蛋
Come on, you fucking son of a bitch!
去你的
Fuck you!
主啊 真是太他妈的惨了
Jesus Christ, what a fucking mess.
你是个蠢货
You're one dumb son of a bitch,
你到底在想什么？
you know that? What the hell were you thinking?
你完全没有守住战场
You completely failed to secure the battlefield.
我要把任务终止了 等待调查  返回基地
I'm shutting this whole thing down pending an inquiry. Get back to base!
嘿 我们得组建一个小队追捕他
- Hey, we gotta set up a squad and pursue him.
不 他们已经逼我们停下来了
- Nope, they're shutting us down.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
没有搞清楚之前暂时不能改变计划
Can't leave the wire till they figure this shit out.
他不能就这样把我们撂在这
Well, he can't just leave us like that.
嘿 我还有三周就回家了
Hey! I go home in three weeks!
伙计 这将会是一个漫长的三周
Man, that's gonna be a long three weeks.
-你还好吗？ -老爸 还好吗？
- How are you? - What's going on, pop?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, baby.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
抱歉 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-我以为你死了 -我不在这吗
- I thought you were dead. - Well, I'm right here.
瞧瞧我
Look at me.
-你没事吧？ -嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
你是我这辈子见过的最美丽的事物了
You're the most beautiful thing I've ever seen.
有个外星人在我肚子里成长着
I have an alien growing inside me.
我的卧室里还有陌生人
- And there's a strange man in my bedroom.
这是我们的卧室
- Well, it's our bedroom.
你的手感觉不同了
Your hands feel different.
噢 不 这就是我的手
Oh, no. They're... they're my hands.
为什么我这么紧张 -我也是
- Why am I so fucking nervous? - Well, I am, too.
-不 你才不紧张 你在撒谎 -我很紧张 我发誓
- No, you're not. You're lying. - Yes, I am. I swear.
我怎么知道这里面的外星人会不会出来抓我呢？
How do I know some alien in there is not gonna come out and grab me?
在午夜时候
In the middle of the night.
那我就得...
Then I'm gonna have to...
把他闷死
choke him out.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
-保证？ -当然了
- Promise? - Yeah, of course.
你为什么总是能迷住我？
Why're you so good with me?
嘿 宝贝 要是出去走走多好啊
Hey, babe. It might be nice to get out.
你听到我说话了吗？
You listening to me?
克里斯
Chris.
亲爱的 你今天想干什么
What do you wanna do today, hon?
我以为可以在家里放松呢
I thought we could just relax here.
好吧 也可以这样
Okay, we do that.
放松吧
Let's relax.
-你在干什么呢 -把脚放在你腿上
- What're you doing? - Putting my foot on you.
你知道这是通往我内心的道路
Well, you know that's... that's the way to my heart.
我过来了
I'm coming over.
这看起来太棒了
And that looks great.
看 他在摸鼻子
Look. He's touching his nose.
-你感觉如何？ -很好
- How are you feeling? - I'm all right.
我只是想让他出去 太累了
I just want him out. I'm tired.
-随时都有可能出来噢 -我希望如此
- Well, it's gonna be any day now. - I hope so.
那你呢 凯尔先生？你感觉如何？
How 'bout you, Mr. Kyle? How're you feeling?
我感觉挺好的 谢谢 女士
I'm feeling good. Thank you, ma'am.
我知道减压很困难
I imagine it's hard to decompress.
没什么
Not really. No.
这是我们第一次离开家
This is the first time we've left the house.
我喜欢待在家里
I'm happy to be home. Yeah.
来 把这个戴上 好吗
Here, put this on for me, would ya?
如果你想要检查什么的话
I think if you wanna check anything out,
就帮我检查一下膝盖吧
you may wanna check out these knees.
-你吸烟吗？ -不 夫人
- Are you a smoker? - No, ma'am.
-喝酒吗？ -口渴才喝
- You drink? - Only when I'm thirsty.
血压170/110
That's 170/110.
-老天 -高吗
- Jesus Christ, Chris. - Is that high?
只有刚刚喝下14杯咖啡的人才会这么高
Not if you've just had 14 cups of coffee.
但是对于整天坐着的人来说...是的
But for someone who is sitting down...
我很感激...帮我量了血压 我会自己看看的
Oh, I appreciate you... taking a look at that. I'll look into it.
-谢谢 -你会注意吗？
- Thank you. - Will you look into it?
是的
Yeah.
你干嘛不跟我一条心
You sabotaged me back there.
那我该怎么办？你什么都不说
What am I supposed to do? You're not talking.
你表现的就像没事似得
You act like it's all okay.
-是没事 我很好 -克里斯 你并不好 知道吗
- It is okay. I'm fine. - You're not fine, Chris, all right?
你的血压有170/110那么高...
Your blood pressure is, like, fucking 170/110. It's like...
我在高速上开着车 天气晴朗 有72度
I'm driving down the freeway. It's sunny. It's 72 degrees.
挺好的 战争正在上演 人们正在死去
I'm fine. There's a war going on. There's people dying.
可甚至都没人谈论这个
No one's even talking about that.
就像没有发生一样
It's like it's not even happening.
我们整天说着电话 过着简单单纯的生活
We're all on our cell phones, living our simple, simplistic lives.
-甚至新闻上都没有 没有人在乎 -克里斯
- It's not even on the news. No one cares. - Chris.
那边战争还在继续 可我居然在去商场的路上
There's a war going on and I'm headed to the mall.
-克里斯 要生了 -我不应该在这里坐着的
- Chris. It's happening. - I'm not supposed to be here.
-怎么了 没事吧？ -要生了
- What's wrong? You okay? - It's happening.
该死 我这就回去
Shit. Okay. I'm gonna go back.
你一定疯了！你知道吗？
- You're fucking crazy! You know that?
没事的 嘿 宝贝
- It's okay. Hey! Baby, baby.
-噢 老天 宝贝 -你看起来真美
- Oh, my God. Baby. - You look beautiful.
我要生了
It's fucking happening.
噢 宝贝
Oh, my baby.
瞧瞧你的妈妈
Look at your mama.
-嘿 -嗨 宝贝
- Hey. - Hi, baby.
-嘿 小伙子 -嘿 宝贝
- Hey, little guy. - Hey, baby.
嘿 小家伙 瞧瞧我们的杰作
Hey, little guy. Look what we did.
看看我们的杰作
Look what we did. Look what we made.
Look what we made.
宝宝在哭 我以为你要去哄的
The baby's crying. I thought you were gonna get him.
不 不用关掉 我已经看到了
No, don't bother turning it off. I already watched it.
得确保你没有找个伊拉克女友 给你发性感视频
Had to make sure you didn't have an Iraqi girlfriend sending you sexy videos.
那是一个狙击手在记录自己的杀人过程 他叫穆斯塔法
That's a sniper recording his kills. That's Mustafa.
他在街上贩卖这些视频 那些都是美国士兵
He sells that shit on the street. Those are American soldiers.
那天我们通话时 是他吗
That day that we were on the phone, was that him? Was it?
克里斯 说说看吧
Chris, just talk about it.
你这样不说话不是在保护我
You're not protecting me by not talking about it.
不 我不想让你脑中有这样的记忆 你明白吗
No, I don't want you getting that in your head, ya understand?
可是我的想象比你告诉我的更糟糕
Well, my imagination is so much worse than anything you could tell me.
-克里斯 -宝贝 他们都是野蛮人
- Chris. - Babe, They're fucking savages.
跟他们没关系
It's not about them.
是关于我们
It's about us.
什么
What?
你得回到我们的生活上来
You have to make it back to us.
好吗
Okay?
第二次行军
欢迎回来 头儿
Welcome home, chief.
琼斯上校正等着呢 旅途还好吧
Colonel Jones is waiting. How was the flight?
-感觉比圣诞假期还长 -那当然
- Damn longer than Christmas. - I bet.
-嘿 你能等会吗？ -好吧 快一点
- Hey. Can you wait a second? - All right. Hurry up.
嘿 小鬼
Hey, grunt!
-克里斯？ -嘿，弟弟
- Chris? - Hey, brother!
嗨
Hi.
你还好吗？你还是完整无缺的吧？
You all right? You in one piece?
我听说你在这里很厉害
I heard you been kicking ass out here,man.
所有人 他们都这么说
All the guys, that's what they've been saying.
-是吗 他们这么说的？ -是的
- Yeah, that's what they say? - Yeah.
你还好吗？你没事吧？噢 见到你真好
How ya doing? You okay? Oh, shit, it's good to see you.
你是我的英雄 老哥 一直都是
You're my hero, bro. Okay? You always have been.
快走 凯尔 上校等着呢
Let's go, Kyle! Colonel's waiting!
传奇？
The Legend?
-怎么了？你没事吧？ -我要迟到了
- What happened? You all right? - Man, I'm gonna miss my ride.
嘿 怎么了？
Hey, what happened?
只是累了 我...我要回家
I'm just tired, man. I'm... I'm going home.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
爸爸也是 他也为你感到骄傲
Dad is, too. Dad's proud of you.
去他妈的这个鬼地方
Fuck this place.
-你说什么？ -去他妈的鬼地方
- What'd you say? - Fuck this place.
头 我们得走了 快
Chief, we got to move! Let's go!
你升职了 恭喜 -谢谢
- You made chief. Congratulations. - Thank you, sir.
格朗斯基死了 很多高级军官都死了
Gronski's gone. A lot of the top brass are.
现在开始新的一章了
Running off a new playbook now.
过去十年里 我研究了叛乱战争
I've studied insurgencies for the last decade.
我知道第一世纪之前发生的每一次斗争
I know every stone thrown since before the first century.
这些战争在敌人心中 都会有一个胜负之分
These wars are won and lost in the minds of our enemy.
是的
Yes, sir.
那是你吗
That you?
这是个十字 是的
That's a crusader cross. Yes, sir.
嗯
Yeah.
你现在在伊拉克已经被头号通缉
You're now the most wanted man in Iraq.
你的脑袋值18万 恭喜你
There's 180,000 on your head. Congrats.
别告诉我老婆 她可能现在就要去领钱了
Well, don't tell my wife. She might take that number right now.
我明白你想要组建一支快速行动小组 追捕屠夫
I understand you wanna put together a direct action squad to hunt the Butcher
是的
Yes, sir.
我们收到了他活动范围的情报
We got some Intel indicating his area of operations.
我想要你把神的恐怖带给这些野蛮人
I want you to put the fear of God into these savages...
然后找他
and find his ass.
好的
Yes, sir.
好了 我们去抓这个混蛋吧
All right, let's go get this motherfucker.
在我们离开之前会有个突击测验
Gonna be a pop quiz before we leave.
-下次再悄悄说 大传奇 -你说呢
- Small words next time, big legend. - What'd you say?
下次再悄悄说
Small words next time.
如果你想听的话 我会告诉你那些故事的
I'll tell you those stories if you want 'em.
-准备一个PPT给你看 -噢 谢了 比尔格斯
- One hell of a PowerPoint, man. - Oh, thanks, Biggles.
总得说些什么吧
Always gotta say something, motherfucker.
你的圣经防弹吗
- That Bible of yours, is that bulletproof?
什么 我放在这里的那本？
- What, the one I put in here?
是的 我只是...从未见你打开过
Yeah. I just... I never saw you open it. I assumed...
上帝 国家 家庭 对吗
God, country, family, right?
你心中有上帝吗？
You got a God?
我信上帝吗？你说什么呢？
I got a God? You getting weird on me?
我在俄勒冈长大 我们家周围就有这种电篱笆
You know, growing up in Oregon, we had this electric fence around our property.
我们小时候抓住他 看谁坚持的久
Us kids'd grab onto it and see who could hold on the longest.
战争感觉就有点想那个
War feels kinda like that.
电从你的骨头里穿过 让你感觉很难抓住别的东西
Puts lightning in your bones and makes it hard to hold on to anything else.
你得坐下来好好想想吗？
Hey, man, you need to sit this one out?
我只相信我们在这里的所作所为
I just wanna believe in what we're doing here.
这里有恶魔 我们已经看到了
Oh, there's evil here. We've seen it.
是啊 遍地都是恶魔
Yeah. There's evil everywhere.
你想让这些混蛋到圣地亚哥或纽约去？
Oh, you want these motherfuckers to come to San Diego or New York?
我们保护的不只是这片烂摊子
We're protecting more than just this dirt.
好吧
All right.
我们去杀了这个混蛋
Let's go kill this fucker.
找到了 就是这栋楼
Bingo. It's the building right here.
东边的任何一间公寓都对着饭店
Any apartment on the east side faces the restaurant.
进去 长官 快 快
Go in, sir. Go, go, go.
安全
Clear.
另一个门
Other door.
-没事 没事 -快点趴在地上
- Okay, okay. Okay. - Get down on the ground right now.
- 把手放在背后 -好的
- Put your hands behind your back. - Okay.
目标安全
Target secure.
克里斯 我看到窗户了
I got the window, Chris.
-设置安防 -好的 我们开始吧
- Set security, boys. - All right, let's get set up.
角落
Corner.
我们把他们带到另一个房间
Let's move them into the other room.
你们都认识他吗？你认识这个家伙吗？
Y'all ask if he knows him. You recognize this guy?
他说不认识
He says he does not.
你呢 小子？你认识这个人吗？
How 'bout you, son? You recognize this face?
你确定？
You sure?
好吧 你告诉他们在我们离开前 他们哪都不能去
Well, you know, you make sure you tell 'em they're not gonna go anywhere until we do.
嘿 你盯着那个窗户
Hey, you keep eyes on that window.
确保要拍下每一个进出的人
Make sure you take pictures of anybody coming and going.
看到什么了？
What do we got?
-16个可疑作战人员进去了 -16个？
- 16 military-aged males have gone in. - 16?
对 他们的顾客比麦当劳还多
Yeah, they serve more customers than a fucking McDonald's.
来 看看这个
Here, check this out.
他还在那里吗？
Is he still in there?
我注意了入口点 他在里面
I clocked one point of entry. He's in there,
但这不是一个简单的突破口
but it's not gonna be an easy breach.
这我一点都不懂
Oh, I don't know about that, man.
可能看见传奇就让他进去了
Probably see The Legend and just let him right in,
你知道 大名人啊
you know, big-time celebrity.
让他在他们的袍子上签名
Ask him to sign their burka.
出现在他们孩子的生日派对上
Appear at their child's birthday parties.
嘿 你怎么回事？我可没有推销我自己
Hey, what is your problem? I didn't... I didn't promote myself.
当然没有 王八蛋 我帮你推销了
Yeah, no shit, motherfucker. I did that for you.
要是我没有给你取个传奇点的外号 你永远都做不了军士长
You woulda never made chief if I hadn't nicknamed you the fucking myth or some shit.
他邀请你跟他一起共进古尔邦节晚餐
He invites you to join him for an Eid Al Adha supper.
他说"在这一天 每个人在我桌上都有一席之位"
He says, "On this day, everyone has a seat at my table."
他真是太大方了
Oh, that's pretty generous of him.
那次好险
That was, like, close, man.
来点黄瓜 把黄瓜浸到醋盆里
Take a cucumber. Take cucumber and put it in a tub with vinegar.
好
Yeah.
放点辣椒和柠檬 然后浸泡一晚
Stick in cayenne pepper and a lemon... and let it soak overnight.
没错 加点伏特加
It's that, and just add vodka.
这是个办法 你想一起吗？
That's the idea. You wanna get in on it?
那就这么决定吧 我是基层股民
Let's do it, dude. I'm a ground-floor investor.
比尔格斯 你这辈子从没做过饭
Biggles, you never cooked a day in your life.
这确实是个问题
Dude, that was the real question.
千真万确
- That was super real.
所有人都支持我们
- All these random people getting behind us.
我的天啊 我都落后了
Oh, my God, I fell in behind the myth.
天啊
Holy shit.
来 伙计 来点羊头 -我得去洗手
- Come on, man. Get some brains. - I gotta wash my hands.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey!
-快去看看 -别动 待在这
- Go check that out. - Stay right here. Stay here.
-嘿 怎么回事 -比尔格斯 帮我一下
- Hey, what the fuck?! - Biggles, help me out.
看到了吗？
See that, Muj?
You see that?
-他妈的怎么回事？ 把塔普带进来
- What the fuck's going on? - Bring the terp in.
噢 该死
Oh, shit.
好了 你快告诉他
All right. Now you tell
他会被送去拘留 而伊拉克法庭可以决定怎么处置他
him that he's gonna be sent off to detention and the Iraqi courts can decide what to do with him.
或者他可以帮我们进入那家饭店楼下
Or he can help us get inside of that restaurant downstairs.
你告诉他 这是他的选择
You tell him. Say it's his choice.
就这样
That's it.
安全
All clear.
好 很好 行动
Good, good. Moving.
突击队准备完毕
Assault team set.
-我们在安全的这边 -目标正在移动
- We're in tight. Security set. - Package is moving.
15米远
15 meters out.
10米
10 meters.
5米
5 meters.
他在敲门
He's knocking.
等等
Hold.
他们在审查他
They're vetting him.
熄灯了
Lights out, Muj.
行动  行动
Execute. Execute.
扔手榴弹
Frag out! Frag out!
-比格尔斯 后方有事吗？ -没有 没有动静
- Biggles, anything coming out the back? - Negative. No movement.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
-D 把他放下 -好的
- "D," Take him down. - Got him.
拿下他
Get him down.
见鬼
Oh, shit!
我们发现一个隧道 小心后面 眼睛睁大了
We found a tunnel. Watch your back. Keep your eyes open.
前方遇袭
Contact! Contact!
前方遇袭  后退
Contact! Drop back!
白色一边 全部防范白色那边
White-side! all security on the white-side!
屠夫行动了
Butcher's on the move.
重复 屠夫行动了 我正在追
Repeat, Butcher's on the move. I'm in pursuit.
屠夫死了 移动你的位置
Butcher's down. Move in your position.
我是说 我提出拘留他 是他自己选的
I mean, I offered him detention. It was his choice.
选错边了 事实就是这样 战争迷雾
Picked the wrong side. It's all there is to it. Fog of war.
克里斯 去他们的 越来越危险了
Yo, Chris! Fuck it, man. Let's go. Shit's getting hairy.
长官 有武装叛乱分子 正朝这边前进 我们得撤离
Sir, we have armed insurgents moving this way. We need to make tracks.
干得漂亮 士官长
Heck of a job there, chief.
-你还想要一个 还是不要了？ -快看 这是什么？
- You want another one, or are you good? - Look. What is this?
不 你抽到什么就是什么 这东西就是这样的
No. Well, you get what it gives you. That's how this thing works.
就算你想要 也不一定能抽到
You don't get that one, if that's the one you want.
我喜欢那个
I like that.
哪个好 威力很大
That's good. That's strong.
克里斯·凯尔 快点 你的卡车好了
- Chris Kyle, come on. Your truck's ready.
你可以移动所有你想要的
- You can move that all you want.
你的卡车好了 不可能
Your truck's ready. Im... impossible.
-把你的信用卡给我 -好的 有意思
- Give me your credit card. - Okay. Interesting.
-我好想已经给你了 -哦 对
- I already gave it to ya, I think. - Oh, right.
什么？把地上那个捡起来
What? Hey, just pick that up off the floor.
一定都要捡起来 后面还有一个
Make sure you get all of them up. Well, you got one back here.
不好意思 先生
Excuse me, sir?
-你是克里斯·凯尔军长吗？ -是的
- Are you chief Chris Kyle? - Yes, sir.
我是麦斯 我们在法鲁贾见过 你救了我的命
My name is Mads. We met in Fallujah. You saved my life.
-是吗？ -没错
- I did? - Yes, sir.
我们被困在房子里 是你和一号陆战队进来救我们的
We were stuck in a house until you came in with the 1st marines.
是你把我抬了出去
You were the one that carried me out.
哇 陆战队救了我们很多次
Oh, wow. Well, the marines saved our ass plenty of times.
-你还好吗？没事吧？ -很好
- How are you? You all right? You holding up? - Great. Yeah.
能活着我就很感激了 这还没...
I'm... I'm just grateful to be alive. It hasn't been...
这很不容易
- Colt. - It hasn't been easy.
你知道
Well, you know.
很多人失去的不止一条腿
A lot of guys lost more than just a leg.
你是不是失去了一些朋友？
Did you lose some friends?
那也是 不过我说的是那些还活着的人
Well, that, too. But I'm talking 'bout the guys that lived.
他们活着回来了 但只是没有...
That made it back, but they're just not...
真正回来的人（指有战后心灵创伤） 你知道吧？
they're just not back, you know?
-他们似乎无法恢复正常 -是的
- They can't seem to get right. - Yeah.
有时间要不你去弗吉尼亚看看？那些家伙会很高兴的
Why don't you come down to the V.A. Sometime? The guys would love it.
他们都知道传奇是谁？
They all know who The Legend is.
-是的 听起来不错 -嘿 小家伙
- Yeah, that sounds like a good idea. - Hey, buddy.
我可以跟你说件事吗？
Can I tell you something?
你爸爸？他是个英雄
Your dad? He's a hero.
真的 他救了我的命 他还...
That's right. He saved my life, and he...
他还帮我回到我女儿的身边
he helped me get back to my little girl.
-所以 谢谢你把他借给我们 -好的
- So, thank you for lending him to us. - Okay.
没有他 我是不会在这里的
I wouldn't be here without him.
我的家人都要感谢你的付出
My family thanks you for your service.
谢谢 好了 照顾好自己
Okay, thank you. All right. Take care of yourself.
-很高兴又见到你 -好的
- It's great to see you again. - All right.
-有空来弗吉尼亚 -好的
- Come down to the V.A. Sometime. - Okay. Yeah.
拿上你的小蜥蜴
Grab your little lizard up there.
谢谢
Thank you.
-不用谢 -祝你愉快
- You're welcome. - Have a good day.
-也祝你愉快 -好的
- You have a good day. - Okay.
好了 我们去见你妹妹
All right, let's go meet your sister, bubba.
嘿 有人帮忙吗？我女儿在哭
Hey. Some help here? My daughter's crying.
我女儿在那里 他在哭呢
That's my daughter over there. I think she's crying.
你能帮我照顾一下吗？不好意思
Can you help tend to her, please? Excuse me.
嘿 你要去哪里
Hey! Hey, where you going?
嘿
Hey!
你可以帮我看看我女儿吗？
Hey, will you tend to my daughter, please?
嘿
Hey!
嘿 看看我女儿 快点
Hey! Tend to my daughter, please! Right now!
只有我自己在创造回忆
I'm making memories by myself.
没人可以跟我分享
I have no one to share them with.
我们为之付出了一生
Yeah, well, we got our whole lives for that.
什么时候开始的
When does that start?
就算你站在这里 但你还是不在这
Even when you're here, you're not here.
我看到你了 我感觉到你了
I see you. I feel you.
但你根本不在这
But you're not here.
所以我讨厌军队
I hate the teams for it.
真的
I do.
你是我丈夫
You're my husband.
你是我孩子的父亲
You're the father of my children,
他们才是你的牵挂
but they're the ones that pull you back.
是的 不过你看 他们等不了 我们可以
Yeah, but, you see, they... they can't wait, and we can.
如果你认为这场战争没有改变你 那你就错了
If you think this war isn't changing you, you're wrong.
不要引火上身
You can only circle the flame so long.
真的
It's true.
前面是一辆凯迪拉克
Cadillac 31 actual,
第三次行军
我们正在马里兰街尾跟随屠夫的信使 完毕
we're tailing the Butcher's courier currently on Maryland street. Over.
嘿 我买戒指了
Hey! Got the ring.
哪买的？这里吗？
From where? From here?
是啊 这里便宜多了
Yeah, man. Fuck, yeah. It's so much cheaper here.
老兄 你在野蛮人这买的
Dude, you bought it from savages?
你怎么知道这不是一颗血钻
How do you know it's not a blood diamond?
你干嘛那么在乎
Oh, what the fuck do you care, man?
你已经在这流了这么多血了 你是传奇
You've spilled so much blood over here. You're The Legend.
那也不是为了一个石头
Oh, that's not for a rock.
随便吧
What the fuck ever, man.
那是伪造的
That's just hypocritical.
放松点 别跟的太近
Hey, ease up on that. No, don't get too close.
我知道
- All right. Hey, I know.
你告诉她你在哪买的戒指了吗
- Did you tell her where you bought it from?
当然没有 我要告诉她是在Zales（美国老牌珠宝店）买的
Fuck no. I'm gonna tell her I got that shit from Zales.
嘿 你还跟着我们呢？
Hey, you still with us, cookie?
就在后面半个街区 我们都准备好了
Just a half block back, baby. We are wet and ready, big giggles.
你知道的 D
You know, "D"...
我预计在20年后 我们会重聚...
I predict in 20 years, we're gonna have a reunion...
你会已嫁作人妇
and you'll be married to a dude.
只要你会洗衣做饭
As long as you cook and clean.
他们在那 -见鬼
- Now, there they are. - Oh, shit.
穆斯塔法已经把他的眼线弄出去了
Mustafa's got his peepers out.
那个混蛋就是凯泽·索斯
This motherfucker is Keyser fucking Soze, bro.
下次你要射准点 别放过他 好吗
Hey, next time you get a clear shot, you try not to miss him, all right?
如果我不去救你的话 我在小巷就可以抓住他了
Well, I would've gotten him in the alleyway if I didn't have to save your ass.
你愿意做我的伴郎吗？
So you gonna be my best man?
只有我一个人？还是其他人都是？
Oh, just me? Or is it gonna be everybody else, too?
只有一个伴郎 伙计
There's only gonna be one best man, dude.
1号车遭到袭击
Vehicle 1 taking fire.
快点 让我来开枪 -好的
- Come on, give me a shot. - All right.
比格尔斯 快
Biggles, move.
安全
Clear.
我搞定了一个
One on me.
我们搞定他了
We got him.
汽车安全
Vehicle is secure.
设置防线 克里斯
Set security, Chris.
没有
Nope.
屋顶安全
Rooftop secure.
难道你不担心她会拿着戒指去店里 问问你花了多少钱？
Aren't you worried that she's gonna take that thing to Zales, find out how much you spent?
-这个 我没想过 -设置防线
- Well, no, I wasn't. - Set security.
-现在我有点担心了 -你应该担心
- Now I'm a little worried about it. - You should be.
你什么意思 难道她会去店里追踪钻石来源？
What do you mean, she can trace the diamond to Zales?
我觉得那不可...
I don't think that's gonna...
你没事吧？你没事的
You okay, buddy? You're all right.
有人负伤 比格尔斯负伤 西北角 屋顶
Got a man down. Biggles is down. Northwest corner, rooftop!
坚持住 伙计
Hang in there, bud.
我这里需要医护兵
I need a corpsman right now!
好了 我们会把你抬起来然后带你去楼下
Okay, bubba. We're gonna pick you up and take you downstairs.
我能走
I can walk.
带他上悍马 带他上悍马
Get him in the Humvee. Get him in the Humvee.
停下来
Breaking off.
我抓住他了
I got him. I got him.
-来 坚持住 比格尔斯 -见鬼
- Come on. Get in. Hang in there, Biggles. - Fuck.
坚持住 比格尔斯
Hang in there, Biggles.
Hang in, Biggles.
-好了 -见鬼 我很抱歉
- It's okay. - Shit, I'm sorry, man.
抱歉什么？你在抱歉什么？
For what? What are you sorry for?
我们上屋顶都是我的错
It's my fault we went on that roof.
我是不是要死了？
Am I gonna die?
不会 比尔格斯 你是个了不起的蛙人
Fuck no, Biggles. You're a fucking frogman.
蛙人是不会死的
Frogmen don't fucking die.
要在伤口上放些沙子
Gonna put some sand in this fucking cut.
我给你找个水壶
We'll get you a fucking canteen of water.
你他妈不会有事的 比尔格斯 坚持住
You're gonna be fucking fine, Biggles. Hang in there.
嘿 克里斯 你确定她能收到那枚戒指吗？
Hey, Chris. You make sure she gets that ring, all right?
当然可以
Sure will.
好的 我们增加抽吸 牵开器准备
All right, let's decrease suction. The retractor, please.
多输点血 他受伤后多久拍的片子
More blood. How long before we get film on him?
我们还要一袋血
We need another unit of blood. Give me a 3 only.
-好了 生理盐水 快点 -用力抽
- All right, saline... now. - More suction.
-握紧你的手 -好的
- Hold your hands right here. - Okay.
交叉配血 我要看那些数据
Type and cross. I need those numbers now.
你看到子弹从哪来的吗？
Did you see where it came from?
起码有1千米远
Yeah, it was more than 1,000 meters out.
敌方只有一个狙击手能射中这一枪
Only one enemy sniper coulda made that shot.
他能挺过来吗？
Will he make it?
把他的点48枪弹夹都打烂了
Took a round off the feed tray cover. Was 48.
看起来情况不好
Doesn't look good.
这是第一个海豹突击队员被击中
That's the first SEAL hit, sir.
操
Fuck!
我们追踪的什叶派出租司机说 有一个7个门的据点
Shi'a cab driver we source is saying there's a stronghold seven doors down.
掩护你们的海军陆战队还在那边激战
Marine units covered your exfil are still engaged there.
如果你想退出并重组 我可以理解 这都看你
I can understand if you want to stand down and regroup. It's up to you.
报复法
Lex talionis.
以牙还牙
Eye for an eye.
我们要重回战场
We're going back out.
-他妈太好了 -好的
- Fucking "A." - Fuck, yes.
我们走吧
Let's go.
好戏开始
It's on.
嘿
Hey!
两公里远
Two klicks out.
过道安全
Hallway clear.
在左边
On the left. Bumping.
过道
Hallway.
过道安全 左边
Hallway clear. On the left.
安全
Clear.
全部安全
All clear.
马克 看来有人匆匆离开了
Hey, Marc. Looks like someone left in a hurry.
-有人被击中 -注意窗户
- Man down! - Cover the window!
有人倒下
Man down!
-注意窗户 -注意窗户
- Cut that window! - Cut that window!
加油 马克
Come on, Marc.
我们走吧 我在这
Let's go, buddy. I got you,
我在这呢 看着我
man. I got you. Look at me. Look at me.
我在这
I got you.
马克死了 兄弟
Marc's gone, bro.
有个海豹队员倒下了 我需要立即护送伤员
I got one SEAL down. I need cabs back immediately.
我们得把他带走
We gotta fucking move him.
荣誉是一些人的追逐
"Glory is something some men chase,
而其他人觉得他们自己偶然发现
"And others find themselves stumbling upon
不期望发现的东西
"Not expecting to find it.
不管怎样 它是一种高贵的姿态
"Either way, it is a noble gesture that one...
人们在其中发现奖赏
"Finds bestowed upon them.
我的问题是
"My question is, when does
荣誉什么时候逐渐消失了 并演变为不当的十字军东侵...
glory fade away and become a wrongful crusade?
还是一种夺取人性命的不正当手段
"Or an unjustified means by which consumes one...
我已经
"Completely? I've...
亲历了战争
"Seen war...
我还亲历了死亡
"And I've seen... death."
特遣队 立正
Detail. Ten-hut!
举枪
Port arms!
准备
Ready!
瞄准
Aim.
开枪
Fire!
准备
Ready.
瞄准
Aim.
开枪
Fire!
准备
Ready.
瞄准 开枪
Aim. Fire!
举枪致敬
Present arms!
马克在两周前写了那封信
Marc wrote that letter two weeks ago.
他有跟你提到过吗
Did he say any of that to you?
克里斯 我想知道你是怎么看待那封信的
Chris, I wanna know what you thought of his letter.
基地组织线人得到风声...
An AQI informant had called in a tip,
比格尔斯刚中弹了
and... Biggles had just been shot.
我们被情绪冲昏了头脑
We were operating out of emotion,
直接走进埋伏中
and we just walked right into an ambush.
不过那不是害死他的元凶
But that's not what killed him.
那封信才是 那信害死了马克
That letter did. That letter killed Marc.
他任其发展 并为此付出了代价
He just... he let go, and he paid the price for it.
在这里签字吗？
Sign in here?
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
-嘿 克里斯 -嗯
- Hey, Chris? - Yeah.
-你在哪？ -我在这里 就在这里
- Where you at, man? - I'm right here. I'm right here.
-该死的 你都瞎成这样了 -是啊 他妈的居然爆炸了
- Shit, you're blind as a bat. - Yeah, it fucking blows.
不过他们说会帮我整容 -谢天谢地
- They say they're gonna fix my face, though. - Oh, thank God.
-你的脸早该整整了 -太早了
- About time. Your face needs some fixing. - It's too soon, man.
-很早嘛？ -相当早
- It is too soon? - Way too soon.
-我听说你求婚了 -是啊
- Hey, I heard you proposed. - Yeah.
太好了
Well, good for you.
你没跟她说那戒指...
You didn't tell her you bought that diamond...
-你跟她说在Zales买的吧？ -不是的
- you told her you bought it at Zales, right? - No.
-你没说？ -没有 我又新买了一个
- You didn't? - No. No, got a new one.
一个比较小的 她爸爸帮挑了一个
It's a smaller one. Her dad helped me out with it.
-那挺好的 -嗯
- Oh, nice. - Yeah.
很不错
Oh, good.
她不会离开我的
She wouldn't leave me, bro.
我要她离开我 她不肯
I told her to go, and she wouldn't leave.
对她真是不公平
She's getting a raw fucking deal.
为什么那么说？别那么说 她还有你
Why would you say that? Don't say that. She's got you.
-还有你的老二 -老二
- All two inches of you. - Two inches.
我很庆幸这是发生在我身上 而不是你身上
Yeah, you know, I'm glad this happened to me and not you.
你肯定应付不了
- Ain't no way you coulda handled it.
可能是的
- Yeah, you're probably right.
他们说你是美国历史上最好的狙击手
So they say you're the deadliest sniper in U.S. Military history.
-真的吗？ -我是这么听说的
- Oh, is that right? - That's what I heard.
-那些混蛋最后在萨德尔城 -你不要回去了
- The bad guys ended up in Sadr City. - You're not going back.
我们要回去 我们要围而歼之
Yeah, we are. We're gonna wall 'em in and hunt 'em down.
别 别这样 你没必要这么做
Nah, come on, man. You don't have to do that.
我们必须这么做 你是我兄弟
Oh, we have to do that. You're my brother.
他们要对你的所做作为付出代价
And they're gonna fucking pay for what they did to you.
了不起 传奇
Hooyah, Legend.
太了不起了
Fucking hooyah.
如果我出事了 你要好好的
Something happens to me, you'd be all right.
你要找另外一个人
You'd find someone else.
你想死吗？
Do you wanna die?
是吗
Is that what it is?
不是
No.
那就告诉我
Then just tell me.
告诉我你为什么要这么做
Tell me why you do it.
-拜托 -我想要你的理解
- Oh, come on. - I wanna understand.
宝贝 一切都是为了你 我这么做是为了保护你
Babe, I do it for you. You know that. I do it to protect you.
-不 你不是 -是的
- No, you don't. - Yes, I do.
我在这里
I'm here.
你的家人在这里 你的孩子没有父亲
Your family is here. Your children have no father.
没错 但我得拯救我的国家
- Well, I have to serve my country.
胡说八道
- That is such fucking bullshit!
不是的 -你不懂什么时候该放弃
- No, it's not. - You don't know when to quit.
你尽力了 我们已经做出了足够的牺牲
You did your part. We've sacrificed enough.
你应该让别人去
You let somebody else go.
-让别人去？ -对
- Let somebody else go? - Yeah.
-我会寝食难安的 -你会找到办法的
- I couldn't live with myself. - Yeah, well, you find a way.
你必须这样
You have to.
我需要重新做回普通人
Okay, I need you to be human again.
我需要你在这里
I need you here.
宝贝 我需要你
Baby, I need you here.
要是你再次离开...
If you leave again...
我不认为你回来时我们还会在这里
I don't think we'll be here when you get back.
过来
Come here.
第四次行军
克里斯
Chris. Oh, man.
我们的位置连续三晚遇到袭击
We've been shot off position three nights in a row, man.
法鲁贾情况很糟 拉马迪更糟糕
Fallujah was bad. Ramadi was worse.
克里斯 这太邪门了
- This shit is fucking biblical, Chris.
这还有别的惩罚者吗？
- Is there any other punishers here?
人手不够了 道贝尔本想回来
Squirrel cycled out. And Dauber was coming back,
可是他老婆把他打晕了
but his wife knocked him up.
克里斯 我要是再挂着彩回家
And if I bring home another rug,
我老婆肯定会把我打死的
my wife'll murder my motherfucking ass, Chris.
都是团队的鬼话 对吧？ -全是团队的鬼话
- Teams and shit, right? - Teams and shit.
伙计 比格尔斯的新闻很火
Man, that Biggles news hit hard, man.
我离开之前去医院看了他
I went to see him in the hospital before I left.
那混蛋什么也看不见了
Motherfucker can't see shit.
比格尔斯已经死了 克里斯
Biggles is gone, Chris.
他昨天做了手术 他在手术台上死了
He was in surgery yesterday, and... he died on that table.
嘿 我是塔雅 我现在不方便接电话
Hey, this is Taya. I can't get to the phone,
请留言
so please leave a message.
是我 我就是想听听你的声音
It's me... Just calling to hear your voice.
我想你们了 我一直在想你说的话
I'm missing you guys. Been thinking about some things you said.
告诉孩子们 我爱他们 我也爱你
Tell the kids I love 'em. I love you, too.
别捡起来
Don't pick it up.
叫你他妈别捡起来
Don't you fucking pick it up.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
快放下
Fucking drop it.
快放下 你这混蛋
Drop it, you little cocksucker.
好了 听好了
All right, listen up.
这些傻帽以为这个T型墙可以帮他们
The head-shed believe this T-wall here will help win the war
阻滞其余的基地组织 并取得胜利
by trapping remaining AQI behind it.
问题是 建造这倒霉玩意的工程师们
Problem is the engineers building the goddamn things
统统被一个深藏在墙后面的狙击手干掉了
are getting picked off by one single sniper from deep behind the wall.
藏得多深？
How deep?
-大约1千米 -是穆斯塔法吗？
- Roughly 1,000 meters. - Is it Mustafa?
-穆什么？ -我不知道
- Mu-who? - I don't know, dude.
就是那个杀死我们朋友比格尔斯的狙击手
The sniper who killed our fucking friend Biggles, man.
管他是谁 我们只要他死
He can be whoever the fuck you need him to be. We just need him dead.
我们会把你送到北边六个街区外的地方领土上
We'll shuttle you six blocks north into enemy territory,
这样你就能在狙击手开枪的时候抓到他 明白吗
which will put you right up under the sniper's nose when he takes his shot, okay?
在沙尘暴中间？
- In the middle of a fucking sandstorm?
把护目镜带上 班比
- Bring your fucking goggles, Bambi.
我们要把这狙击手击毙 明白吗 整装出发
We need to shut this shooter down. Understood? Gear up.
-是 长官 -是 长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
安全 行动
It's clear. Move out.
安全
Clear.
-我们冲锋 你们掩护 -好的
- We're maneuver. You're base. - Yep.
出发
Go.
Go!
-安全 -走
- Clear. - Moving.
走  走
Go! Go!
全部安全
All clear.
设置防线
Set security.
街道不太平 先不要开枪
The streets are crawling. Hold your fire.
简直和漫画书一样
Enter the fucking sandman.
-有人受伤 -有人倒下
- Man down! - Man back!
该死的
Shit!
从东边射击的
Shot came from the east!
我们的方向搞错了
We set up in the wrong fucking direction.
没关系 先别开枪 我们正下方有麻烦
Doesn't matter. Hold your fire. We got uglies right below us.
我看到1900码外有东西
I got something 1,900 yards out.
该死 他甚至都看不到那么远
Fuck, you can't even see that far out.
不要开枪 会让我们暴露的
Hold your fire. You'll expose us all.
他说的没错 传奇 这样不好
He's right, Legend. No bueno.
纠正 是2100码以外
Correction. It's 2,100 yards out.
那都快2英里了 克里斯 不可能射中的
That's more than a mile. Impossible shot, Chris.
是他
It's him.
这是任务组指挥
This is task unit bruiser.
我正看着目标 启动快速反应部队 完毕
I got eyes on target. Initiate QRF. Over.
收到 快速反应部队已经出动 预计需要20分钟
Copy that. ET on quick reaction force is 20 minutes out.
-他盯上我们的人了 -你能确定是他妈？
- He has eyes on our guys. - Can you confirm it's him?
是他
It's him.
-是他 -克里斯 你来决定
- Oh, it's him. - It's your call, Chris.
快速反应部队还有20分钟才到
Quick reaction force is 20 minutes out.
你不要行动
You'll stand the fuck down!
如果有机会就开枪吧
If you got it, take it, man.
瞄准目标越小 失误越小
Aim small, miss small.
为比格尔斯报仇
Do it for Biggles.
你害死我们了 传奇
You just fucked us, Legend.
目标已倒下
Tango down.
我们需要快速反应部队 越快越好
We need QRF ASAP!
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
他盯上我们的人了
He had eyes on our guys.
-我把他干掉了 -嗯
- And I took him out. - Yeah.
现在我们成了活靶子了
Now we're fucked like a football bat.
比格尔斯会感到骄傲的
Biggles would be proud.
你成功了 克里斯
You did it, Chris.
E7K 警告你 有敌人接近你们的位置
Echo 7 kilo, be advised you have enemy approaching all directions of your pos.
在南边 该死的 传奇 操你的
White-side! Goddamn it, Legend. Fuck!
好 来吧 我们走
Yeah, let's go. Come on.
好的 上房顶有两条路
All right, I see two ways up onto the roof.
我们要把两个楼梯口都守住
We wanna lock both staircases.
节省弹药
Conserve ammo.
尝尝厉害 混蛋
Get some, motherfuckers.
E7K 正前方有两架重机枪
Echo 7 kilo, you have tango-heavy gun on your green-side.
保证有效活力
We're taking effective fire,
南边 瞄准了打
white-side! Effective fire, white-side!
D 我就剩两个弹夹了 我们该走了
- "D", I'm down to two mags! We gotta move!
-别停火啊 伙计
- Don't stop fucking shooting, man!
快速反应部队被困在三个街区以外的地方
QRF's stuck three blocks out.
-我没弹药了 -3点钟方向 最后一个弹夹了
- I'm out! - 3 o'clock. Loading last mag.
我只有一个弹夹了
I've only got one mag left!
我没子弹了 有人有多的吗
I'm black! I'm black! Anybody got a mag?!
我们托不住了 我们得走了
We can't hold 'em any longer! We gotta move!
这些家伙成了活靶子
Those guys are sitting ducks.
-我可不想被拖到街上去 -就这样 来吧
- I don't wanna get dragged in the street. - That's it. Do it.
叫过来吧
Call it in.
里约2号请求投掷炸弹
This is Rio 2 Bravo requesting ordnance drop.
-坐标04837959 -那目标位置跟你们的位置一样
- Grid number 04837959. - That target location is your position.
我当然知道是我的位置
I know my fucking position!
他们就在我们上面 丢下来就行了
They're right on top of us. Just drop it!
毒蛇34号 开始进行最后攻击
Viper 34, move to final attack heading.
毒蛇34号 收到 30秒后抵达
Viper 34. Roger. 30 seconds out.
喂？
Hello?
宝贝
Baby?
克里斯 宝贝 我...宝贝 我听不到 喂？
Chris? Baby, I ca... baby, I can't hear you. Hello?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我准备好回家了 -什么
- I'm ready to come home. - What?
我已经看到那建筑了
I have the building in sight.
怎么了？
What's happening?
我准备好回家了 宝贝
I'm ready to come home, baby.
克里斯？
Chris?
上面空气很不好 我无法继续盘旋
It's pretty bad air up here. I can't hold this much longer.
告诉飞行员 "丢下去吧"
Tell the pilot "Turn it loose."
毒蛇34号 开火吧
Viper 34. Fire away.
目标未命中
Target missed.
该死
Shit.
我们得撤离了 快点 快走
We need to exfil now! Let's go! Let's move!
我们得走了
We gotta move!
E7K 正前方有撤离路线
Echo 7 kilo, green-side is clear for exit.
我找到出口了 我要从南边出去
I got the out. Green-side pole on my go!
他们在楼顶上
They're on the roof.
我们走
Let's go!
最后一个
Last man!
退回去
Get to the back!
走 走 走
Go! Go! Go!
快点 进来 进来
Come on! Inside, inside!
快上卡车 快上卡车 我们得走了
Get in the truck! Get in the truck now! We got to go!
快点 我们得出去了
Come on! We got to get out now!
让我上去
Let me up.
快点 让我上去
Come on, let me up. Come on.
克里斯在哪？
Where's Chris?
他刚就在我后面啊 克里斯在哪？
He was just behind me. Where is Chris, man?
把门打开
Open the fucking door.
快停车
Stop the goddamn rig!
他在哪？克里斯！
Where is he?! Chris!
克里斯 快
Chris, come on!
-快点 -保持停车 伙计
- Come on! - Hold the fucking vehicle, man!
我们不能丢下你 快点 克里斯 抓住我的手
We can't leave you! Come on, Chris! Grab my hand! Come on, Chris!
拉他进来 快点
Pull him in now!
快 克里斯
Come on, Chris!
-喂？ -嘿 是我
- Yeah? - Hey, it's me.
我...我刚收到条奇怪的短信 你好像是在飞机上什么的
I just... I got this weird message that you were on a plane or something?
是的 是的 我之前发的
Yeah. Yeah, I got out early.
真的吗
You did?
那么 你在德国还是...其他哪里？
So, what, are you in Germany, or... where?
没有 我在这里...
No, I'm here. I'm...
我在国内
I'm stateside.
你回家了？
You're home?
那你在干什么？
What... what are you doing?
我想我需要一点时间
I guess I just needed a minute.
克里斯 孩子们
Chris, the... the kids
很想见见你 你都走了9个月了
are dying to see you. It's been nine months.
我回家了
I'm coming home.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
嗯 我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
宝贝 回家吧 好吗
Babe, come home. Okay?
你知道...我们很想你
You know, we... we miss you.
好的
Okay.
嘿 克里斯？
Hey, Chris?
宝贝
Babe.
亲爱的 我...我要出去了
Hon, I'm... I'm going outside.
-去拿 -高一点
- Get it. - Higher.
瞧瞧你 我又能见到你了 宝贝 多好啊
Look at you. I can see your face again, babe. Looks good.
-很好 -看起来不一样了
- Oh, good. - Looks different.
比赛是在这周六
So the game's this Saturday.
他是队里最高的孩子
You know, he's the tallest kid on the team.
医生说他能长到6英尺4英寸
Doctor said he could be 6'4".
是不是很高？
Isn't that insane?
我等不及跟你一起看他比赛了 看着其他孩子跳到他身上 我都疯了
I can't wait for you to see him play. I go so crazy, though, when the other kids jump on him.
我需要你在这里 像正义使者一样
Like, I need you there as, like, a leveler,
你明白我的意思吗？
you know what I mean?
嘿 也许你可以做教练
Hey, maybe you could even coach, you know?
肯纳的那颗牙快掉了
'Kenna's gonna lose that tooth,
我好担心 她会不会在做梦的时候吞下去了
and I'm so worried she's gonna swallow it, like, in her sleep or something.
她说要让你帮她拔下来 只能让你拔
And she said she'd let you pull it, but only you.
你会帮她吗？
Would you do that?
克里斯！
Chris!
我接到一个非常有趣的电话 是你妻子打来的
I got a very interesting phone call. It's from your wife.
她告诉我烧烤那发生的事
She told me about the barbecue.
是啊 很不幸 是的
Yeah, that was unfortunate. Yeah.
感觉好像有些事情应付不来了
Things seem like they got a little out of hand.
-你担心吗？ -不 先生
- Are you worried? - No, sir.
也就是说 你对已经发生的 还有将要发生的 都不担心吗
So you're not worried about what happened, or what might happen?
不 我不会担心那个
No, sir, I'm not worried about that.
我问你个问题 克里斯
Let me ask you a question, Chris.
你在国内待了多久？
How much time did you spend in-country?
-大概4次行军 -那么就是1000多天
- Well, four tours, so... - That's like, what, 1,000 days?
对 差不多吧
Yeah, sounds about right.
要是我告诉你 海军记载说你
Would you be surprised if I told you
一共杀了160多敌人 你是否感到惊讶？
that the Navy has credited you with over 160 kills?
你有没有想过...
Do you ever think that...
或许你看到的 做过的某些事情 是你不希望发生的呢？
you might have seen things or done some things over there that you wish you hadn't?
噢 那不是我 不会的
Oh, that's not me. No.
-什么不是你？ -我只是在保护我的战友
- What's not you? - I was just protecting my guys.
他们想要杀死我们的战士...
They were trying to kill our soldiers, and...
我很乐意站在上帝面前清点我杀死的每一个敌人
I'm willing to meet my creator and answer for every shot that I took.
所谓的
The thing that...
让我难过的 是我没办法拯救的那些队友
haunts me are all the guys that I couldn't save.
我很愿意留在那边
You know, I'm willing and able to be there,
但我没有 我在这里 我不干了
but I'm not. I'm here. I quit.
也就是说你希望拯救更多战友？
So you wish you could've saved more guys?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
其实你可以去这家医院的任何一间病房看看
You know, you can walk down any hall in this hospital.
我们还有许多需要拯救的战士
We got plenty of soldiers need saving.
想要走走吗？
Wanna take a walk?
当然
Sure.
好的 我给你看点东西
All right. I wanna show you something.
我还吸烟
I still smoke.
不过多亏这习惯保住了我的右手
Can't be too mad at it 'cause it kinda saved my right hand.
怎么说？
How so?
我被炸飞的时候 我的两只手都在方向盘的地步
When I got blown up, I had both of my hands on the bottom of the steering wheel.
就在爆炸发生前 我把手移开
And right before the explosion went off, I took my hand off,
去拿了香烟 然后含在嘴里
grabbed a cigarette, stuck it in my mouth.
在我点烟的时候 爆炸就发生了
And when I went to go light it, the explosion happened.
整个方向盘都炸飞了 我的左手也就没有了
And it took the whole bottom of the steering wheel and my left hand off.
我很幸运 我还有右手
And I was lucky that I had this.
虽然我右手也受伤了 不过...
I mean, it still fucked up my right hand, but...
-是的 -我还有右手
- Yeah. - ...I still got it.
-那你还吸烟吗？ -是的 还吸
- And you still smoke? - Yeah, I still smoke.
没打中 偏右三英尺
Miss. Three inches to the right.
加油 韦恩 你能做的更好
Come on, Wynn. You can do better than that.
往右边一点
Bring this to the right.
确保你两只眼睛都睁开着 扣动扳机来个惊喜
Make sure you keep both eyes open. Let that trigger surprise you.
我们不是在朝坏人射击 我们在朝纸射击
We're not shooting bad guys. We're shooting paper.
那传奇不要干扰我 听起来怎么样
How about The Legend stops trying to fuck up my shot? How about that?
你可以打中一次吗？
How about you hit one?
-击中 -这就对了
- Hit! - There you go.
小子 打红心
Bull's eye, boy. Damn,
我还是没法重振当年雄风
if that don't feel like I got my balls back.
你干嘛要在这里和我们在一起？
Why you spending all this time with us, man?
我知道你有家人
I know you got a family.
我听说你战前收集了不少靴子
I heard you had a boot collection before the war?
所以我在想 我们的尺码看起来一样
So I was thinking, I saw we were about the same size.
说真的 伙计 你为什么要这样？
Seriously, man. Why do you do it?
我们是彼此照顾的 对吧
Well, we take care of each other, right?
看你能不能连续两次打中吧
Let's see if you can't hit two in a row.
加油 你可以的
Come on, man. You got this.
-中了 -漂亮
- Hit! - Nice.
-中了 -真棒
- Hit! - Goddamn.
现在谁是传奇了？
Who's the legend now?
这个称号你最好别要 相信我
That's a title you don't want. Trust me.
欢迎来到德克萨斯
嘿 你能跳下来吗 来帮我搬东西
Yo, will you hop down? I'll give 'em to you.
-要再来一个吗？ -好的
- You add one more? - Yeah.
-好的 搬进去吧 -好的
- All right, take 'em inside. - All right.
来这里
Come here.
外面的日子不错啊 对吧
It's not a bad life out here, is it?
脸上还有笑容
Got a smile on his face.
看来蛮开心的
Looks cheery to me.
只管做自己的事
Just doing his thing.
跟他告别吧
Wave goodbye to him.
噢 该死的 是谁
Oh! Fuck, who is that?!
-噢 宝贝 是你吗 -当然了
- Oh! Babe, is that you? - Yep-A-Doo-Dee!
-宝贝 我伤到自己了 该死的 -什么
- Baby, I fucking hurt myself. Shit. - What?
我没事  我没事
No, I'm all right. I'm all right! I'm all right. Fuck.
-宝贝 对不起 -没事
- Baby, I'm sorry. - It's okay.
怎么了 别...
What happened? Don't...
你知道那玩意可以让心跳停止
You know that it's a heck of a thing to stop a beating heart.
知道
Yeah.
这就是第一次我们要一起完成的原因
That's why we're gonna do it together for your first time.
好的
All right.
现在 记住了 你要冷静...
Now, remember, you gotta be calm...
自信
confident...
绝对不迟疑
and you never hesitate.
-好的 -你明白了吗 儿子
- All right. - You got it, bubba?
-明白 -感觉还好吗？
- I got it. - You feel good?
嗯
Yeah.
2013年 2月2日
举起手来 小姑娘
Hands in the air, little lady.
举起手来
Hands in the air.
还是放抽屉里去吧
Now, you drop them drawers.
慢慢的丢进去
But you drop 'em nice and easy.
噢 宝贝 瞧瞧你
Oh, baby, look at you.
-瞧瞧你 -看看你
- Look at you. - Look at you.
我能跟你说件事吗？
Can I tell you something?
-去跟法官说吧 -停下来
- Tell it to the judge. - Stop it.
不 我为你感到骄傲 而我告诉你的还不够多
No. I am so proud of you, and I don't tell you enough.
我为你感到骄傲 你是一个很好的父亲
I'm so proud of you. And you're such a great father.
我很高兴 我的丈夫回来了
And I am so happy that I've got my husband back.
我也知道 走到这一步 你做出了多大的努力
And I also know how hard you fought to get here.
你值得我努力
You're worth fighting for.
告诉我一些别的事吧
Now tell me one other thing.
你是不是...把这些牛仔裤打褶了
Did you... did you pleat those jeans?
是的 女士 我觉得它们应该就在中间
Yes, ma'am. I believe they're right down the middle.
噢 你又变成一个合格的老牛仔了
Oh, you're just a regular old cowboy again.
没错 还有你要不真的 放抽屉里去吧
That's right. Now, why don't you...why don't you really drop them drawers?
我又没有随身带抽屉 宝贝
I'm not wearing any drawers, baby.
我有4分钟
I got four minutes.
就这么快吗？
Is that all it takes?
不 只需要2分钟
No, it takes two minutes.
不过之后 我还想用两分钟看着你
But then again I want two minutes to look at you.
你不是要去山上吗？
Aren't you going to the range?
你要带谁去？
Who are you taking out?
有个陆军 他妈妈一直叫我去
This marine. His mama kept asking me.
他把车停在小学里 然后说"你能帮一下我儿子吗"
She parks cars at the elementary school, and she said, "Can you help out my son?"
我就在想 今天是我真正能帮她的那一天 所以...
And I just thought...today's the only day I can really do it, so...
只需要下午一会功夫 我就回来了
It's gonna be just a little bit of the afternoon. I'll be back.
好的
Yes!
你确保把那些东西放抽屉里 -爸爸
- You make sure you keep them drawers... - Daddy.
-怎么了 怎么了 -爸爸 你想玩"空中着陆"吗？
- What's up? What's up? - Dad, you wanna play Skylanders?
不行 我现在没法玩 我回来的时候玩吧
No, I can't play right now. I'll do it when I get back, boy.
但是 你看你在第8级上 那没什么用的
But, see, you're on level 8, and that doesn't work.
我应该在第4级上的 我不想...
I gotta be on level 4. And I don't want...
我想要赢 你要让我赢
I wanna win. You gotta let me win.
没门
No way!
-戳大熊 -戳什么？
- Poke the bear! - Poke the what?
-戳大熊 -戳什么
- Poke the bear! - Poke the what?!
戳大熊
Poke the bear!
不 你应该这样叫...
No! You're supposed to roar, like...
像什么？像野兽一样吗？
Like what? Like a beast, right? Like what?
好了 孩子 照顾我们的妈妈 好吗
All right, bubba. Y'all look after our women, okay?
-好的 -好的 责任重大哦
- Yeah. - Okay. It's a big responsibility.
你可以的吧
You up for it?
好的 回头见 宝贝
All right. See you later, baby.
-我爱你 -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you back.
-你怎么样？还好吗？ -很好
- How are you? You good? - Good.
我们要开两个小时的车 然后开开枪
We're gonna go about a two-hour drive and shoot some guns
或许还可以在路上聊聊天 你说呢？
and maybe have a little conversation along the way. What you say?
-好的 -好的 我们走吧
- Yeah. - All right. Let's go.
-谢谢 -好的
- Thank you. - Yep.
嘿 你吃东西了吗？你饿不饿？要不要路上找点吃的？
Hey, you eat yet? You hungry? You wanna get something on the way?
那一天克里斯·凯尔被他要去帮助的老兵杀害了
导演与制片
克林特·伊斯特伍德
编剧
杰森·哈尔
改编自传作者
克里斯·凯尔与史考特．麦坤和金·戴福利斯
制片
罗伯特·洛伦兹
安德鲁·莱泽
制片
布莱德利·库珀
彼得·摩根